<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="presentation" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-11-14" />
	<meta name="customised" content="false" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/presentation.css" type="text/css" media="screen" />
<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/presentation-print.css" type="text/css" media="print" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	
	
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<settings>
 	<param name="delayedMarking" value="true" />
</settings>
  <questions/>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
<div id="instruction">
	Look at this list of possible problems and read any you think applied to you in this task.
</div>
</header>
	
<section id="body">
	<img class="rightFloat" src="../media/set10_07.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"  />
	
	<div id="presentation">
	<h6><p>A. Wrong interpretation</p></h6>
	
	<ol>
		<li>Practise listening to the radio and repeating the information you hear. Ask yourself what the statements and remarks mean.</li>
		<li>When you study, practise reading the instructions out loud (under your breath, if you are embarrassed!), so you are careful to read every word.</li>
	</ol>
	
	<h6><p>B. Fluency</p></h6>
	<ol>
		<li>Practise describing things (ANYTHING – from a chair, to a computer) either to yourself, to a friend, or to anyone who will listen.</li>
		<li>Use who-, which- and what- questions to derive answers which you can compose into a descriptive account.</li>
		<li>Play games in which you and friends take turns to talk for just one minute on any topic.</li>
		<li>Play the same game, but without saying "the", to make it more fun.</li>
	</ol>
	
	<h6><p>C. Grammar</p></h6>
	<ol>
		<li>Get out your revision and grammar books, and do as many basic grammar exercises as you can stand.</li>
		<li>Then do some more!</li>
		<li>Pick three grammar exercises you find easy, then do one that you find really difficult.</li>
		<li>Write a list of five grammar points that you have particular difficulties with – then revise one a day, for five days.</li>
	</ol>
	
	<h6><p>D. Vocabulary</p></h6>
	<ol>
		<li>Read stories in English.</li>
		<li>Read newspaper articles in English that are about subjects you find interesting.</li>
		<li>Read comics in English.</li>
		<li>Watch English language films.</li>
		<li>Make vocabulary lists and carry them with you.</li>
		<li>Keep a notebook with you and write down the names of things you see – look them up in the dictionary. Look at them again and again. As your list gets longer and longer, keep looking back. It's amazing how fast your vocabulary will increase.</li>
	</ol>
	
	<h6><p>E. Pronunciation</p></h6>
	<ol>
		<li>Listen to the radio, watch English language films.</li>
		<li>Work out what your personal problem sounds are.</li>
		<li>Practise them.</li>
		<li>Record yourself speaking, and listen to yourself.</li>
		<li>Practise again.</li>
	</ol>
	
	<h6><p>F. Communication skills</p></h6>
	<ol>
		<li>Learn the lists of useful phrases given in different units of this course.</li>
		<li>Play a game with a friend – describe an object or idea, without naming it, and see how quickly your friend can guess what it is.</li>
		<li>Think of some particularly memorable events in your life – practise describing them to a friend, in just a few sentences.</li>
		<li>If you can, use the internet to practise natural, informal English.</li>
	</ol>

</div>
</section>
</body>
</bento>