<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="presentation" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-10-31" />
	<meta name="customised" content="true" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/presentation.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking/>
		<feedback wrongonly="false"/>
		<buttons feedback="false" marking="false"/>
		<exercise/>
		<misc/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
  <questions/>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	What will I learn in this unit?
</header>
	
<section id="body">

<img class="rightFloat" src="../media/LE_SP_001.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>

<div id="presentation">
<h1><p>General introduction to the speaking test</p></h1>

<p>You will ...</p>


<p>1. &#xA0; refresh key points and timing for the speaking test.<br/>
2.  &#xA0; watch video clips of a candidate and the examiner starting the speaking test.<br/>
3. &#xA0; watch candidates describing their home towns.</p>

<p>The speaking test is a one-to-one interview which assesses how well you can communicate in English. The interview lasts for 11-14 minutes and has three parts.</p>


<p>Part 1: You answer general questions about yourself, your life and interests.<br/>
Part 2: You give a short talk on a particular topic.<br/>
Part 3: You discuss with the examiner some issues related to your talk.</p>

<p>Now look at a more detailed description of the three parts of the test:</p>
<h6>Part 1: Introduction and interview</h6>
<p>Examiner introduces him/herself and confirms candidate's identity. Examiner interviews candidate using verbal questions based on familiar topic frames. Timing: 4-5 minutes</p>
<h6>Part 2: Individual long turn</h6>
<p>Examiner asks candidate to speak for 1-2 minutes on a particular topic based on written input in the form of a general instruction and content-focused prompts. Examiner asks one or two questions at the end of the long turn. Timing: 3-4 minutes (including 1 minute preparation time)</p>
<h6>Part 3: Two-way discussion</h6>
<p>Examiner invites candidate to participate in discussion of more abstract nature, based on verbal questions thematically linked to Part 2 prompt. Timing: 4-5 minutes</p>
</div>
</section>


</body>
</bento>