<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion" type="gapfill" date="2011-10-27" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking/>
		<feedback groupbased="true" wrongonly="false"/>
		<buttons/>
		<exercise samelengthgaps="true"/>
		<misc splitscreen="true"/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<questions><GapFillQuestion source="q1"><answer value="iii " correct="true"/><answer value="III" correct="true"/><answer value="3" correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q2"><answer value="v " correct="true"/><answer value="V" correct="true"/><answer value="5" correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q3"><answer value="vii " correct="true"/><answer value="VII" correct="true"/><answer value="7" correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q4"><answer value="i " correct="true"/><answer value="I" correct="true"/><answer value="1" correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q5"><answer value="iv " correct="true"/><answer value="IV" correct="true"/><answer value="4" correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion></questions></script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	
		
		Questions 1-5. The reading passage has five sections A-E. Choose the most suitable headings for sections A-E from the list of headings below. Write the appropriate numbers (i-viii) in gaps 1-5. There are more headings than sections, so you will not use them all.
		
</header>
	
<section id="body">
	<br/><ol id="questionList"><li id="1">Section A  <input id="q1" width="100" /></li><li id="2">Section B  <input id="q2" width="100" /></li><li id="3">Section C  <input id="q3" width="100" /></li><li id="4">Section D  <input id="q4" width="100" /></li><li id="5">Section E  <input id="q5" width="100" /></li></ol>
</section>
<section id="readingText">
	<p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Student Motivation To Learn</b></font></p><p align="left"><font color="#000000">Infants and young children appear to be propelled by curiosity, driven by an intense need to explore, interact with, and make sense of their environment.  Unfortunately, as children grow, their passion for learning frequently seems to shrink. Learning often becomes associated with drudgery instead of delight. A large number of students – more than one in four – leave school before graduating.  Many more are physically present in the classroom but largely mentally absent; they fail to invest themselves fully in the experience of learning.</font></p><p align="left">Awareness of how students' attitudes and beliefs about learning develop and what facilitates learning for its own sake can assist educators in reducing student apathy.</p><p align="left"><b>SECTION A</b>Student motivation naturally has to do with students' desire to participate in the learning process. But it also concerns the reasons or goals that underlie their involvement or non-involvement in academic activities. &nbsp;Although students may be equally motivated to perform a task, the sources of their motivation may differ.A student who is intrinsically motivated undertakes an activity "for its own sake, for the enjoyment it provides, the learning it permits, or the feelings of accomplishment it evokes" (Mark Lepper 1988). An extrinsically motivated student performs "in order to obtain some reward or avoid some punishment external to the activity itself," such as grades, stickers, or teacher approval (Lepper).</p><p align="left"><b>SECTION B</b>Children's home environment shapes the initial attitudes they develop toward learning. When parents nurture their children's natural curiosity about the world by welcoming their questions, encouraging exploration, and familiarizing them with resources that can enlarge their world, they are giving their children the message that learning is worthwhile and frequently fun and satisfying.&nbsp;When children are raised in a home that nurtures a sense of self-worth, competence, autonomy, and self- efficacy, they will be more apt to accept the risks inherent in learning. Conversely, when children do not view themselves as basically competent and able, their freedom to engage in academically challenging pursuits and capacity to tolerate and cope with failure are greatly diminished.&nbsp;Once children start school, they begin forming beliefs about their school-related successes and failures. The sources to which children attribute their successes (commonly effort, ability, luck, or level of task difficulty) and failures (often lack of ability or lack of effort) have important implications for how they approach and cope with learning situations.</p>&nbsp;The beliefs teachers themselves have about teaching and learning and the nature of the expectations they hold for students also exert a powerful influence (James Raffini 1993). As Deborah Stipek (1988) notes, "To a very large degree, students expect to learn if their teachers expect them to learn."&nbsp;Developmental changes comprise one more strand of the motivational web. For example, although young children tend to maintain high expectations for success even in the face of repeated failure, older students do not. And although younger children tend to see effort as uniformly positive, older children view it as a "double-edged sword" (Carole Ames 1990). To them, failure following high effort appears to carry more negative implications – especially for their self-concept of ability – than failure that results from minimal or no effort.<p align="left"><b>SECTION C</b>Does it really matter whether students are primarily intrinsically or extrinsically oriented toward learning? A growing body of evidence suggests that it does.J. Condry and J. Chambers (1978) found that when students were confronted with complex intellectual tasks, those with an intrinsic orientation used more logical information-gathering and</p>decision-making strategies than did students who were extrinsically oriented.&nbsp;Students with an intrinsic orientation also tend to prefer tasks that are moderately challenging, whereas extrinsically oriented students gravitate toward tasks that are low in degree of difficulty. Extrinsically oriented students are inclined to put forth the minimal amount of effort necessary to get the maximal reward (Lepper).&nbsp;Although every educational activity cannot, and perhaps should not, be intrinsically motivating, these findings suggest that when teachers can capitalize on existing intrinsic motivation, there are several potential benefits.<p align="left"><b>SECTION D</b>Classroom climate is important. If students experience the classroom as a caring, supportive place where there is a sense of belonging and everyone is valued and respected, they will tend to participate more fully in the process of learning.&nbsp;Various task dimensions can also foster motivation to learn. Ideally, tasks should be challenging but achievable.  Relevance also promotes motivation, as does "contextualizing" learning, that is, helping students to see how skills can be applied in the real world (Lepper).</p>&nbsp;In addition, defining tasks in terms of specific, short-term goals can assist students to associate effort with success (Stipek). Verbally noting the purposes of specific tasks when introducing them to students is also beneficial (Jere Brophy 1986). &nbsp;Extrinsic rewards, on the other hand, should be used with caution, for they have the potential for decreasing existing intrinsic motivation.<p align="left"><b>SECTION E</b>A first step is for educators to recognize that even when students use strategies that are ultimately self-defeating (such as withholding effort, cheating, procrastination, and so forth), their goal is actually to protect their sense of self-worth (Raffini).</p>&nbsp;A process called attribution retraining, which involves modeling, socialization, and practice exercises, is sometimes used with discouraged students. The goals of attribution retraining are to help students to (1) concentrate on the tasks rather than becoming distracted by fear of failure; (2) respond to frustration by retracing their steps to find mistakes or figuring out alternative ways of approaching a problem instead of giving up; and (3) attribute their failures to insufficient effort, lack of information, or reliance on ineffective strategies rather than to lack of ability (Brophy 1986).&nbsp;Other potentially useful strategies include the following: portray effort as investment rather than risk, portray skill development as incremental and domain-specific, focus on mastery (Brophy 1986).&nbsp;Because the potential payoff – having students who value learning for its own sake – is priceless, it is crucial for parents, teachers, and school leaders to devote themselves fully to engendering, maintaining, and rekindling students' motivation to learn.<p align="left">Linda S. Lumsden, ERIC Digest, Number 92, June 1994.</p><p align="left"><font size="2"></font></p><p align="left"><font size="2"></font></p><p align="left"><font size="2"></font></p>
</section>
<section id="rt2001">
	<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">This reading passage is all about what motivates pupils to learn. In this exercise you must match headings to sections in the text. It is similar to exercises you've met so far in Units 3 and 8 where you matched headings to paragraphs. In this case, a section may include more than one paragraph.</font>&nbsp;Remember that these are headings, not pieces of information. Make sure that the heading you choose sums up the content of the whole section, not just a part of it.</p>
</section>
</body>
</bento>