<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion" type="targetspotting" date="2011-10-27" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking instant="true"/>
		<feedback neutral="true"/>
		<buttons feedback="false" marking="false"/>
		<exercise/>
		<misc/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<questions><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="t1" correct="false"><feedback source="fb1"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="t2" correct="false"><feedback source="fb2"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion></questions></script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	What will I learn in this unit?
</header>
	
<section id="body">
	<img class="rightFloat" src="../media/LC_AR_001.JPG" mode="1" id="1001"  /><p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Academic Reading Passage 1</b></font>Do animals talk?You will read a book extract comparing animal communication with human language.</p><p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Academic Reading Passage 2</b></font>Language and the brainYou will read a book extract describing the role that the brain plays in human language.</p><p align="left"><b>Question types</b>You will attempt two question types.<u><g id="t1">Matching</g></u><u><g id="t2">Sentence completion</g></u></p><p align="left"><font size="2"></font></p>
</section>
<section id="fb1">
	<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"><b>Matching Information to Paragraphs</b></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">(i.e. scanning and identifying location of information)</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">At first glance, this may seem similar to the 'matching headings to paragraphs' exercise. However, whereas a heading summarises the content of a paragraph, here you are looking for a piece of information that happens to be included in a paragraph, but that does not represent the whole meaning of that paragraph. In fact, this exercise type is more like short answer questions or table completion because you are searching quickly for specific information, but instead of writing down what you find, you simply say where you found it.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Don't read from the start of the text until you reach the required information. If you have already surveyed the text and have a 'mental map', you should know in which part of the text the information is likely to be found. Go straight to the paragraph or section you think it is located in and start reading carefully from that point onwards.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Unlike short answer questions or table completion, the information you're looking for will not be just a few words or a number. The phrases in the questions usually summarise an idea or a concept that is included in the paragraph, so you're trying to find whole sentences, not just a couple of words. Underline the key words in the phrases given in the exercise and look for synonyms - that is, words that mean the same thing - in the section of the text you think contains the information.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">It's a good idea to cross off items from the list as you find them, and to underline the part of the text where you found the information. This will give you a record of how far you've got with the exercise and, if you think you've made a mistake, you can easily go back to the relevant part of the text to check.</font></p>
</section>
<section id="fb2">
	<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"><b>Sentence Completion</b></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">('Free-standing' sentences/sentences in a flow chart)</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">This exercise involves completing sentences which paraphrase or summarise a piece of information in the text. As always, make sure you read the instructions carefully. The words must be taken from the text and you mustn't change them in any way. You will be given a word limit for the gaps, which is usually up to three words, but you ought to check this is the case. The gapped words are not normally contractions, so if you find you need to use a contraction to stay inside the word limit, then your answer is probably wrong.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">The sentences follow the order of the text, so this should give you an idea of where to look to find the answer. If you need a two or three word phrase to fill a gap, then these words will be found close together in the text, in the same sentence. Don't try to 'make' phrases by collecting words from completely different parts of the text.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Remember that the completed sentence must be grammatically correct. It helps if you look at the words immediately before and after the gap. If these words are prepositions, articles or auxiliary verbs, then you should know what kind of word (noun, verb or participle for example), will follow.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">This exercise is intended to check if you have understood the main points of the text, so the words and phrases that are missing are important ones that carry a lot of meaning. Once you've completed a sentence, read it to yourself. Does it summarise a main point or piece of information from the text? If not, then you need to think again about your answer.</font></p>
</section>
</body>
</bento>