<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="proofreading" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-11-14" />
	<meta name="customised" content="false" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	
	
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<settings>
 	<param name="delayedMarking" value="true" />
</settings>
  <questions/>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	Read this sample answer to the writing task in the previous exercise and find the mistakes. There are 23. Click on them.
</header>
	
<section id="body">
  <img class="rightFloat" src="../media/SS_AW_018.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>
  <p align="left">The traditional method of dealing with young people who <g id="t1">brake</g> the law has been to send them to prison. However, in many countries the juvenile crime rate has continued to rise and <g id="t2">goverments</g> have had to look for other ways to tackle the problem, such as sentencing young offenders to community service. In common with all forms of punishment, this has both advantages and disadvantages.</p>
  <p align="left">Community service has a number of benefits. First of all, offenders devote their time and energy to giving something back to the community that has <g id="t3">sufferred</g> as a result of their criminal acts. <g id="t4">Conseqently</g>, they make amends in the most <g id="t5">possitive</g> way possible by helping those most <g id="t6">afected</g>. Secondly, they gain a sense of pride from the work they do and they also <g id="t7">aquire</g>&#xA0;<g id="t8">usefull</g> skills, which raises their self-esteem. <g id="t9">Finaly</g>, by working for and in the local community, they not only become more involved in it, but also develop feelings of <g id="t10">responsability</g> towards their fellow citizens, and can begin to <g id="t11">biuld</g> relationships based on respect. This, in turn, reduces the <g id="t12">likelyhood</g> of their re-offending.</p>
  <p align="left">However, community service also has some drawbacks. Firstly, it may be regarded as a 'soft' option by some offenders and, as a result, it will not act as an effective <g id="t13">deterrant</g> to crime.  Furthermore, <g id="t14">althougth</g> community service is <g id="t15">apropriate</g> for many young offenders, it is not <g id="t16">siutable</g> for all of them. Some are too dangerous to be allowed to move around <g id="t17">freelly</g> in the community and need to be <g id="t18">inprisoned</g>, both for their own safety and for that of others. Lastly, it may be difficult to implement community service satisfactorily. <g id="t19">Wheras</g> in prison convicts are <g id="t20">consentrated</g> in a small area where they can be supervised by a small staff, offenders sentenced to community service are dispersed over a wide area and providing adequate supervision may <g id="t21">proove</g> both costly and impractical.</p>
  <p align="left">In conclusion, I <g id="t22">beleive</g> that community service is an effective form of punishment for young offenders who have <g id="t23">commited</g> only minor offences. For those who repeatedly break the law or commit more serious crimes, alternative methods of punishment may be necessary.</p>
  <p align="left">
    <font size="2"/>
  </p>
</section>

<section id="fb1">
  <p align="left">break</p>
</section>

<section id="fb2">
  <p align="left">governments</p>
</section>

<section id="fb3">
  <p align="left">suffered</p>
</section>

<section id="fb4">
  <p align="left">Consequently</p>
</section>

<section id="fb5">
  <p align="left">positive</p>
</section>

<section id="fb6">
  <p align="left">affected</p>
</section>

<section id="fb7">
  <p align="left">acquire</p>
</section>

<section id="fb8">
  <p align="left">useful</p>
</section>

<section id="fb9">
  <p align="left">Finally</p>
</section>

<section id="fb10">
  <p align="left">responsibility</p>
</section>

<section id="fb11">
  <p align="left">build</p>
</section>

<section id="fb12">
  <p align="left">likelihood</p>
</section>

<section id="fb13">
  <p align="left">deterrent</p>
</section>

<section id="fb14">
  <p align="left">although</p>
</section>

<section id="fb15">
  <p align="left">appropriate</p>
</section>

<section id="fb16">
  <p align="left">suitable</p>
</section>

<section id="fb17">
  <p align="left">freely</p>
</section>

<section id="fb18">
  <p align="left">imprisoned</p>
</section>

<section id="fb19">
  <p align="left">Whereas</p>
</section>

<section id="fb20">
  <p align="left">concentrated</p>
</section>

<section id="fb21">
  <p align="left">prove</p>
</section>

<section id="fb22">
  <p align="left">believe</p>
</section>

<section id="fb23">
  <p align="left">committed</p>
</section>

<section id="fb24">
  <p align="left">rehabilitate</p>
</section>

<section id="fb25">
  <p align="left">community</p>
</section>

<section id="fb26">
  <p align="left">community</p>
</section>

<section id="rt2001">
  <p align="left">
    <font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">When you are checking for mistakes in a composition, remember to check for spelling mistakes as well.</font>
  </p>
</section>

</body>
</bento>