<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="proofreading" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-11-14" />
	<meta name="customised" content="true" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/targetspotting.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking instant="true"/>
		<feedback wrongonly="false"/>
		<buttons/>
		<exercise hiddentargets="true" proofreading="true"/>
		<misc/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
  <questions/>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	<img class="rightFloat" src="../media/LE_Task01b.jpg" mode="16" id="1004"  />
		
		Read this sample answer to the writing task in the previous exercise and click on the mistakes. There are 10. To see the IELTS Writing Task 1 again, click on the icon on the right.
		
		
		Writing Task 1
</header>
	
<section id="body">
<div id="targetspotting">
  <img class="rightFloat" src="../media/LE_AW_7.jpg" mode="1" id="1003"/>
  <p align="left">The chart &#xA0;<g id="t1">is showing</g>&#xA0; the &#xA0;<g id="t2">numbers</g>&#xA0; of boys and girls in Australia who take part in five different leisure activities. Overall we can say that boys' participation in these activities &#xA0;<g id="t3">was</g>&#xA0; greater than that of girls.</p>
  <p align="left">It is immediately clear that the most popular leisure time activity among this age group is watching television. Almost all children in Australia &#xA0;<g id="t4">are spending</g>&#xA0; their free time in this way and this is true for both boys and girls. However, in three of the four remaining activities, boys' participation &#xA0;<g id="t5">was</g>&#xA0; significantly greater than that of girls.</p>
  <p align="left">The next most popular activity is playing computer games. Four out of five boys enjoy these games, compared to almost &#xA0;<g id="t6">three in four</g>&#xA0; girls. Bike riding follows computer games in terms of popularity. Just under three-quarters of boys say they like cycling compared to approximately &#xA0;<g id="t7">a fifth</g>&#xA0; of all girls. The only activity which &#xA0;<g id="t8">has become</g>&#xA0; more popular with girls than with boys is art and craft. Just over 50 per cent of girls enjoy this pastime compared to only about &#xA0;<g id="t9">a quarter</g>&#xA0; of boys.</p>
  <p align="left">The figures &#xA0;<g id="t10">are seeming</g>&#xA0; to suggest that the stereotypical image of boys being more active and girls more artistic or creative still holds some truth in Australian society.</p>
  <p align="left">
    <font size="2"/>
  </p>
  </div>
</section>

<section id="fb1">
  <p align="left">
    <font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">shows: Present simple is the correct tense here.</font>
  </p>
</section>

<section id="fb2">
  <p align="left">
    <font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">percentages: The vertical axis tells us that the figures are percentages.</font>
  </p>
</section>

<section id="fb3">
  <p align="left">
    <font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">is: No time period is referred to in the graph, simple present is the appropriate tense.</font>
  </p>
</section>

<section id="fb4">
  <p align="left">
    <font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">spend: No time period is referred to in the graph, simple present is the appropriate tense.</font>
  </p>
</section>

<section id="fb5">
  <p align="left">
    <font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">is: No time period is referred to in the graph, simple present is the appropriate tense.</font>
  </p>
</section>

<section id="fb6">
  <p align="left">
    <font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">three in five: The figure for girls is 58 per cent, which is almost three in five.</font>
  </p>
</section>

<section id="fb7">
  <p align="left">
    <font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">three-fifths: The figure for girls is 56 per cent, which is approximately three-fifths.</font>
  </p>
</section>

<section id="fb8">
  <p align="left">
    <font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">is: No time period is referred to in the graph, simple present is the appropriate tense.</font>
  </p>
</section>

<section id="fb9">
  <p align="left">
    <font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">a third: The figure for boys is 34 per cent, which is approximately a third.</font>
  </p>
</section>

<section id="fb10">
  <p align="left">
    <font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">seem: No time period is referred to in the graph, simple present is the appropriate tense.</font>
  </p>
</section>

<section id="rt2001">
  <p align="left">Remember - there is no 'correct' answer for Writing Task 1. There are many possible approaches to the task and the sample answer given here is just one way the information shown in the chart can be described.</p>
</section>

</body>
</bento>