<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion" type="targetspotting" date="2011-10-27" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking instant="true"/>
		<feedback neutral="true"/>
		<buttons feedback="false" marking="false"/>
		<exercise/>
		<misc/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<questions><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="t1" correct="false"><feedback source="fb1"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="t2" correct="false"><feedback source="fb2"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="t3" correct="false"><feedback source="fb3"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="t4" correct="false"><feedback source="fb4"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="t5" correct="false"><feedback source="fb5"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="t6" correct="false"><feedback source="fb6"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion></questions></script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	What will I learn in this unit?
</header>
	
<section id="body">
	<img class="rightFloat" src="../media/ST_AR_001.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"  /><p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Academic Reading Passage 1</b></font>RobomothsYou will read an article describing research into methods of controlling insects electronically.</p><p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Academic Reading Passage 2</b></font>No place like homeYou will read an article discussing the possibility of life on other planets.</p><p align="left"><b>Question types</b>You will attempt six question types.<u><g id="t1">Matching headings to paragraphs</g></u><u><g id="t2">Classification</g></u><u><g id="t3">Multiple choice</g></u><u><g id="t4">Yes, No, Not given</g></u><u><g id="t5">Matching (cause and effect)</g></u><u><g id="t6">Summary completion</g></u></p>
</section>
<section id="fb1">
	<p align="left"><b>Multiple Heading to Paragraphs or Sections/Choosing from a Bank of Headings</b></p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">This exercise type tests how quickly you can skim through a text in order to understand the main ideas discussed and how they are developed and organised. You'll probably find that this exercise comes before exercises that ask you to find specific information, such as sentence completion or short answers. If this is not the case, it's still a good idea to start with this exercise, because it will help you get an overall picture of what the text is about. You shouldn't spend too long on this exercise; you're supposed to be skimming quickly.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">The headings listed in the exercise summarise the main points of each paragraph. And, in fact, the first sentence of each paragraph, sometimes called the topic sentence, does exactly the same. So, the best way to deal with this exercise is to read through the list of headings, underlining key words, and then skim through the text, reading only the first sentence of each paragraph.</p><p align="left"></p>	<p align="left"><font color="#000000">Now take each heading one by one. Go back again to the topic sentences. Look out for words that mean the same as those given in the headings. When you find a match, make a note on the text and tick the heading off the list. If you're still not sure about which heading matches, read the last sentence of the paragraph, which usually summarises what has been said. Be careful, though. There are usually one or two distractors: headings which include some of the key words, but which actually don't match any of the paragraphs. Don't just rely on vocabulary that seems to match. Read the topic sentences of each paragraph carefully enough to understand the idea which it expresses before deciding on a match.</font></p>
</section>
<section id="fb2">
	<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"><b>Classification</b></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">This is similar to the matching exercise, with the difference that you are not making one-to-one matches, but grouping pieces of information, names or other details into categories or classifications.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Read the instructions carefully and make sure you know which letters represent each category. Remember that some categories are a combination of two other categories in the same exercise. For example, 'Painting', 'Sculpture' and 'Both Painting and Sculpture' could be three possible categories. Similarly, a category can exclude all others in the exercise. For example 'Neither Painting nor Sculpture' is a possible category.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Next, read the list of statements carefully. For each one, underline key words and decide which part of the text is likely to give the answer by looking for the same words or words which mean the same in the text. Remember that the questions in this exercise do not follow the order of the text, so you will have to keep moving about the text to locate information. Some statements may need you to skim the text to find information from different parts. This is especially true of the combination categories I mentioned earlier. Once you think you have found the relevant sentence, read it and the sentence immediately before and after it.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Make sure that at the end of the exercise you have used all the categories at least once. If this isn't the case, you've probably made a mistake.</font></p>
</section>
<section id="fb3">
	<p align="left"><font color="#000000"><b>Multiple Choice (x1)</b></font></p><p align="left"><font color="#000000">(Students choose 1 answer for 1 mark)</font></p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">This exercise consists of a series of questions about the text, with a number of possible answers to choose from. In this case, there's only one correct answer per question.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Sometimes the questions focus on the meaning of the whole text. For example, you may be asked to choose a suitable title. In this case, it's important to keep in mind the overall gist of what you've read. Some of the answers may be true statements about a specific detail, but they don't summarise the whole text.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Other multiple choice questions focus on a specific part of the text. If you have already skimmed through the passage, you will be able to find the relevant section quickly. For each question, read only the paragraph that you think contains the answer.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">With any multiple choice exercise, don't go searching through the text until you've compared the alternatives carefully and made sure you are clear about how each one is different. Read the whole question and all the distractors. Some of the distractors will contain words that are mentioned in the text, but don't immediately assume that this is the correct answer. You ought to consider the meaning of the whole sentence, not just single words. </p>
</section>
<section id="fb4">
	<p align="left"><b>Yes/No/Not Given</b></p><p align="left"><font color="#000000">(Writer's views/opinions/claims)</font></p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">At least one of the three texts in the reading test will include detailed logical argument, where the writer expresses views on a certain issue, or explains and discusses views held by others. Yes/No/Not Given is the most likely exercise type with texts like this. This exercise tests how well you can identify and understand views or claims in the text.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">You are given a list of statements and asked whether they agree with or contradict the opinions of the writer, or if no opinion is expressed concerning this issue. As with all exercises that focus on a particular detail of the text, the first thing you should do is identify which section of the text each question refers to. Once you've found the right part of the text, read through the relevant paragraph carefully.</p>
</section>
<section id="fb5">
	<p align="left"><b>Matching sentence beginnings to endings</b></p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">In many ways these exercise types are similar to multiple choice questions. Exercises typically consist of the first half of a series of statements with a number of possible outcomes or endings to choose from.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Read all the questions and answers carefully and be sure you understand how the different options change the meaning of the complete sentence. From the vocabulary, try and predict what the topic of the listening will be. At this stage you might be able to guess some answers and eliminate some options.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left"><font color="#000000">Be careful – some distracters in the options might be synonyms (words that mean the same thing) with words in the listening, but you shouldn't assume that this is the correct answer. You need to consider the meaning of the whole sentence, not just individual words.</font></p>
</section>
<section id="fb6">
	<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"><b>Summary Completion</b></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">(Using words from the passage/using words from a box)</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">This is usually the last of the exercises for a given text, so by the time you reach this exercise you should already have a good idea of what the text is about and how it is organised. You are given a short, gapped summary of the main points of the whole text or the main points of an important part of the text. You will be asked to fill the gaps in the summary with words or phrases taken either from the text or from a word box given with the exercise.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">The first thing to do is read the summary once through, without worrying about the gaps. Decide if the summary refers to only a particular section of the text. If so, go directly to that section and read it through again carefully. If, on the other hand, the summary deals with the main points of the whole passage, make a note of how many separate points the summary mentions. Go back to the text, skim through it until you have found these same points and underline or number the relevant parts of the text. Once you have done this, you will find it easier to move back and forth, comparing the summary with the original text. Now you are ready to fill the gaps.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">As with all gap-filling exercises, check the instructions carefully. There will be a limit to the number of words you can use in a gap. Usually this is up to three words, but check this is the case.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">If you have to use words or phrases from the text, make sure that they fit grammatically. The words on either side of the gap will help you understand whether a noun or a verb or a whole phrase is needed. Remember, though, that this is a reading test and not a grammar test. If a single word is needed to fill the gap, you can be sure that it will be a word that carries meaning on its own. In other words, articles, auxiliary verbs and pronouns are not gapped on their own. The missing words are key words in the text.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">If you have to use words form a word box rather than the text, remember that the box contains more words and phrases than you need. Again, the grammar of each sentence in the summary will help you choose the correct word. Don't be tempted to use a word from the box just because you saw the same word in the passage. Some of the words in the box will be taken from the text, but sometimes the words you need to use are synonyms of important words from the passage. Cross off the words as you use them and write them in the gaps on the question paper. Before you finally copy your answers onto the answer sheet, read through the summary and check that what you've written makes sense and agrees with the information in the passage.</font></p>
</section>
</body>
</bento>