<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion" type="gapfill" date="2011-10-27" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking/>
		<feedback groupbased="true" wrongonly="false"/>
		<buttons/>
		<exercise/>
		<misc/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<questions><GapFillQuestion source="q1"><answer value="meteorologist " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q2"><answer value="genetic " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q3"><answer value="psychiatric " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q4"><answer value="Astronomers " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q5"><answer value="chemistry " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q6"><answer value="ecological " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q7"><answer value="mathematical " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q8"><answer value="biologists " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q9"><answer value="geology " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q10"><answer value="linguistics " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q11"><answer value="zoology " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q12"><answer value="psychologist " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q13"><answer value="physicist " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q14"><answer value="Seismologists " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion></questions></script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	Fill the gap in each sentence with an appropriate noun or adjective.
</header>
	
<section id="body">
	<img class="rightFloat" src="../media/ST_TV_006.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"  /><br/><ol id="questionList"><li id="1">I've always been fascinated by the weather. I've wanted to be a <input id="q1" width="100" /> since I was a child.</li><li id="2">Even if we inherit a <input id="q2" width="100" /> disorder, we will not necessarily develop it ourselves. We can pass it on to our children though.</li><li id="3">She has been admitted to a <input id="q3" width="100" /> ward in hospital and is being given lots of drugs to calm her down.</li><li id="4"><input id="q4" width="100" /> do more than casually look through telescopes. They find the answers to fundamental questions about the Universe.</li><li id="5">Discoveries in <input id="q5" width="100" /> have led to entirely new industries, including plastics, frozen foods and synthetic textile fibres.</li><li id="6">Discovering that laundry detergents are one of the major causes of poor water quality is an example of the kind of <input id="q6" width="100" /> research that ultimately helps to improve our environment. </li><li id="7">A great many children today are not able to do simple <input id="q7" width="100" /> calculations. They have become too dependent on calculators.</li><li id="8">Among other things, marine <input id="q8" width="100" /> study the life cycle of fish so that we can learn to catch them efficiently and do not overfish the seas and oceans.</li><li id="9">A degree in <input id="q9" width="100" /> could lead to a career in mining or in advising construction companies on the suitability of materials for heavy engineering projects such as dams.</li><li id="10">There are several different disciplines within <input id="q10" width="100" />. Phonology and language acquisition are two of the core fields of study.</li><li id="11">People who have studied <input id="q11" width="100" /> at university may find employment in zoos or aquariums or they may become involved in wildlife management and other conservation fields. </li><li id="12">He has been going to see a <input id="q12" width="100" /> and seems to be much better. They have been discussing all the problems he faced as a child.</li><li id="13">The unit of energy, the joule, is named after the famous <input id="q13" width="100" /> James Perscott Joule, who established that all forms of energy (electrical and heat) are basically the same and are interchangeable.</li><li id="14"><input id="q14" width="100" /> have devised two scales to measure earthquakes: the Richter Scale, which measures the energy released at the epicenter of an earthquake (magnitude), and the Mercalli scale, which measures the strength of shaking produced by an earthquake at a certain location on the Earth's surface (intensity).</li></ol>
</section>
</body>
</bento>