<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="gapfill" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-10-31" />
	<meta name="customised" content="true" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking overwriteanswers="true"/>
		<feedback groupbased="true" wrongonly="false"/>
		<buttons/>
		<exercise samelengthgaps="true"/>
		<misc splitscreen="true"/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
  <questions>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q1" block="b1">
      <answer value="The McLoughlin Brothers" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="The McLouglin Bros." correct="true"/>
      <answer value="The McLoughlin Bros" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="McLoughlin Brothers" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="McLouglin Bros." correct="true"/>
      <answer value="McLoughlin Bros" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q2" block="b2">
      <answer value="dice" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q3" block="b3">
      <answer value="Civil War soldiers" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="soldiers" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q4" block="b4">
      <answer value="lithography" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="colorful lithography" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="colourful lithography" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q5" block="b5">
      <answer value="domesticity" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="cult of domesticity" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q6" block="b6">
      <answer value="Charles Lindbergh" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="Lindbergh" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="Admiral Byrd" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="Byrd" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q7" block="b7">
      <answer value="plastic" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="wood" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="metal" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="plaster of Paris" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q8" block="b8">
      <answer value="wood" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="plastic" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="metal" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="plaster of Paris" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q9" block="b9">
      <answer value="metal" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="plastic" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="wood" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="plaster of Paris" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q10" block="b10">
      <answer value="plaster of Paris" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="plastic" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="wood" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="metal" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	Read the passage on the left. Using NO MORE THAN THREE WORDS from the passage, answer the questions on the right.
</header>
	
<section id="body">


  <ol id="splitquestionList">
    <li id="1">Which game company was established in 1858?</li>
	<input id="q1"/>
	<br/>
    <li id="2">What game pieces were regarded as extremely immoral before the end of the 19th century?</li>
	<input id="q2"/>
	<br/>
    <li id="3">Who did Milton Bradley produce miniaturised games for?</li>
	<input id="q3"/>
	<br/>
	<li id="4">What production technique was dropped at the turn of the last century to make games more affordable?</li>
	<input id="q4"/>
	<br/>
    <li id="5">What aspect of the late 1940s lifestyle was reflected in the games of that period?</li>
	<input id="q5"/>
	<br/>
    <li id="6">Give the name of ONE real person who inspired board game designers in the first half of the 20th century.</li>
	<input id="q6"/>
	<br/>
    <p align="left">List&#xA0;<b>FOUR</b>&#xA0;materials which have been used to make game pieces.<br/></p>
    <li id="7">
      <input id="q7"/><br/>
    </li>
    <li id="8">
      <input id="q8"/><br/>
    </li>
    <li id="9">
      <input id="q9"/><br/>
    </li>
    <li id="10">
      <input id="q10"/>
    </li>
	</ol>
  
</section>

<section id="readingText">

  <h8><p>Board Games</p></h8>
  <h2><p>How it all began</p></h2>
  
  <p>The first documented board game in America, A Traveler's Tour Through the United States, appeared in 1822. Demand for this new form of pastime was limited, and it wasn't until W. &amp; S.B. Ives successfully marketed the Mansion of Happiness in 1843 that production began to pick up. The McLoughlin Brothers, one of the most successful board game producers of the 19th century, started its business in 1858.</p>
  
  <p><img class="photo1" src="../media/LE_AR_002.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/></p>

  
  <p>Strict Victorian mores guided early board game producers. The games were viewed as educational tools, intended to teach children lessons in history, geography, and good moral conduct. Dice were frowned upon, owing to an early Puritan belief that the tiny cubes were "instruments of the Devil". As the century drew to a close, the rules governing board game design eased and inventors were free to create games that were more entertaining and less moralistic, including examples based on baseball, yachting, and horse racing.</p>
  <p>
 As the middle class continued to expand, the desire for new leisure activities spurred the board game industry. W. &amp; S.B. Ives, though it had been one of the first American companies to manufacture games, soon faded from the scene. In its place, four firms rose to dominance: the McLoughlin Bros., known for bright-colored, lithographed boxes and game boards; Milton Bradley, the first firm to manufacture compact game boards for Civil War soldiers; Parker Brothers, started in 1888 after George Parker bought the rights to the W. &amp; S.B. Ives company's games; and Selchow and Righter, the firm that obtained the U.S. rights to Parcheesi in 1874.</p>
  <p>By 1900, dozens of companies were producing board games for distribution across the United States. Newspaper publishers even printed full-page game boards in their Sunday papers from time to time. New trends appeared, such as games involving skill and strategy that targeted adult audiences. While the public benefited from the competitive pricing and the wider selection of games that resulted from the increase in production, the colorful lithography that had been the norm during the 19th century fell victim to cost-cutting measures. As the 20th century progressed, game boards became smaller, block letters replaced elaborate lithography and plastic supplanted wood and metal as the material of choice for game pieces.</p>
  
  <h7><p>Portrait of an Era</p></h7>
  <p>
		"These were more than just games," says Lee Dennis, one of the foremost game collectors in America and a frequent lecturer on the subject, "they were boxes of history." Advancements in transportation, Presidential elections and military conquests were just some of the events that inspired new board games. Drawing on the influences around them, designers of the '30s and '40s developed themes that reflected the times in which they lived.
	</p>
  <p>
  	Characters from the Sunday comics soon appeared on board games like the Dick Tracy Detective Game (Whitman Pub.), Oh, Blondie (Whitman Pub.), and the Little Orphan Annie Game (Milton Bradley). Radio serials were another popular pastime in America's pretelevision days. Eddie Cantor's Tell It to the Judge (Parker Bros.) and Fibber McGee and the Wistful Vista Mystery Game (Milton Bradley) were two examples translated onto game boards. </p>
   <p>
Educational games held their appeal and were produced in large numbers. The 1930s Game of Voyage Around the World (Milton Bradley) came on the heels of the late-1920s Flight to Paris (Milton Bradley) and the Lindy Flying Game (Parker Bros.), inspired by Charles Lindbergh's historic 1927 flight. Other educational games from the 1930s and '40s included Admiral Byrd's South Pole Game (Parker Bros.) and Go to the Head of the Class (Milton Bradley), a precursor of sorts to today's Trivial Pursuit (Parker Bros.).
  </p>
  <p>
Game production rose to new heights late in the 1930s and then slowed during the Second World War, as paper, metal, and other materials were rationed and the nation turned to wartime production. Some games of this era came equipped with plaster of Paris pieces and an apologetic note from the manufacturer explaining the need to ration metal as part of the war effort. The late 1940s welcomed the baby boomers and witnessed the rise of the cult of domesticity. Games like Let's Furnish a House for All the Family (Parker Bros.) reflected these cultural phenomena as well.
  </p>
  <p>By the early 1950s, television had entered the American home. Fictional characters and celebrities from this new medium would find their way onto board games in the decades that followed, including Howdy Doody and Davy Crockett in the 1950s, Batman and the Addams Family in the 1960s, and the Partridge Family and Charlie's Angels in the 1970s. Interest in these later games has been growing among young collectors during recent years.</p>
  <p>Bruce E. Johnson, Country Living, December 1997.</p>

</section>

<section id="rt2001">
  <p align="left">Questions 1-10 - Short answer questionsDo not spend too much time on this exercise. The questions focus on very specific pieces of information. Analyse the questions first, looking for key words, and then skim through the passage quickly to find the information. You do not need to read the whole text in detail. Remember, you should use a maximum of three words for each answer and these must be taken from the reading passage.</p>
  <p align="left">Question 7-10What kind of materials do you think are used to manufacture board games? You will have to go back to the beginning of the passage and scan the whole text to find these. Three of the answers can be found close together, but one is on its own in a later part of the text. And remember - you are looking for materials used to make game pieces, not other parts of board games.</p>
</section>

</body>
</bento>