<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion" type="multiplechoice" date="2011-10-26" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[			
		list {
			list-style-type: decimal;
			margin-left: 0; 
			padding-left: 20px; 
			padding-bottom: 12px; 
		}
		p {
			padding-bottom: 12px; 
		}
		.no-padding {
			padding-bottom: 0px; 
		}
		.h1 {
			font-size: 12px;
			font-weight: bold;
			color: #3A00FF;	
		}
		#noscroll span[draggable="true"] {
		   float: left;
		   width: 140px;
		} 
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking instant="false"/>
		<feedback wrongonly="false"/>
		<buttons feedback="false"/>
		<exercise/>
		<misc splitscreen="true"/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<questions/></script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	
		Complete the Multiple Selection exercise below.
</header>
	
<section id="body">
	<br/><ol id="questionList"></ol>
</section>
<section id="readingText">
	<p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Why Newspapers will flourish in the Years Ahead</b></font>&nbsp;How have the surviving daily newspapers responded so vigorously to the challenge posed by television? First, they switched their focus from the evening to the morning. Television pre-empted the evening time that once had been set aside for reading the paper. Those newspapers that fought this change generally lost and went out of business. At the Toronto Star, we know our very survival depended on switching from evening to morning publication.&nbsp;Our second response to the television challenge was to produce a paper with much more colour. You can't compete with colour television in black and white.&nbsp;The third way we responded to the challenge of television was to become more interpretive, more analytical. A paper at mid-century might have had 23 brief stories on its cover page. Today a newspaper's front page has five to seven in-depth articles. This development toward more in-depth coverage is one that we have welcomed. It builds upon the Star's tradition of fighting for social justice.&nbsp;The fourth and final way we responded to television was the simplest, but probably the most profound of all. We remained faithful to our traditional strengths. Each media outlet that provides news has its own virtues. Radio can be listened to while driving to and from work. Television has motion and immediacy. But newspapers have something no other medium has: they distill the news, compress it and make it accessible.</p>&nbsp;The problem with TV news is that you can't fast-forward. If the viewer is interested in the fourth story in that night's "line-up", as those in television call it, he or she has to watch the first three stories, as well.&nbsp;In a newspaper, though, there might be seven headlines on the front page. Let's say you're somewhat interested in four of these. You read the first three paragraphs of these stories and, if the paper is well-written, you've gotten the gist of the day's news. You have already received as much information as you would have in a 15-minute TV newscast. That's why today's newspaper industry is flourishing.&nbsp;Many people will insist that television might not kill the newspaper industry, but the Internet will. A report from Forrester Research in the United States concluded in 1997 that "Newspapers are in big trouble and they're going to get hammered."&nbsp;News like that we can do without. The Internet is a wonderful news medium. It will find an important place in consumer's lives, along with other media. Yet I am confident that, while the Internet will change our business dramatically over the next 20 years, we can live with it. In fact, newspapers and the Internet will complement each other. &nbsp;Derrick de Kerckhove, director of the McLuhan Program in Culture and Technology at the University of Toronto, states the issue well: "The job of the newspaper is to sort out items which are relevant to the public's interest, over and above those which address purely individual needs." In other words, the issues we should know about will fall through the cracks because we didn't request them - the Quebec ice storm, for example. That's why customized on-line newspapers don't work.&nbsp;The reverse, however, is true for business information. I am interested in specific subject area, the communication industry, for example, and customized reports can be waiting for me on-line when I arrive at work. That's worth paying for.&nbsp;The final reason our readers will stay with us is the "feel" of a newspaper compared to a screen. Would anyone really look forward to a Sunday morning curled up in an easy chair with a cup of coffee and a computer screen? I don't think so. A newspaper in its present from works. You can pick it up and put it down whenever you want. &nbsp;The reality is that people use the Internet during the day for business information and in the evening for personal interest, and that hour spent in the evening cuts into television viewing, not newspaper reading. Very few people are on-line over breakfast.&nbsp;Edmund Burke once wrote: "You can rarely plan the future by the past." Newspaper are entering an uncertain time, but they will continue to prosper in the years ahead because of their natural strengths and their ability to adapt.&nbsp;David Galloway, Thunderbird On-line Magazine, December 2000, Vol.iii, Issue ii.
</section>
<section id="rt2001">
	<p align="left">Questions 1-7 - Multiple selectionThe first half of this passage is about how a newspaper dealt with the threat posed television. How do you think newspapers adapted to the challenge? How did newspapers in your country react to the threat of television? Which of the reactions in the list seems the most likely to you? Which four apply to the newspaper discussed in the passage?&nbsp;The second half discusses the advantages newspapers have over other media. Which of the strengths listed would you say apply to newspapers? Which three are discussed in the passage? </p>
</section>
</body>
</bento>