<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="gapfill" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-10-31" />
	<meta name="customised" content="false" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking/>
		<feedback groupbased="true" wrongonly="false"/>
		<buttons/>
		<exercise/>
		<misc/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
  <questions>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q1" block="b1">
      <answer value="that are involved" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="who are involved" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q2" block="b2">
      <answer value="leaving" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q3" block="b3">
      <answer value="which fill" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="that fill" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="which are filling" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="that are filling" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q4" block="b4">
      <answer value="looking" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q5" block="b5">
      <answer value="offered" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q6" block="b6">
      <answer value="who live" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="that live" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="that are living" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="who are living" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q7" block="b7">
      <answer value="consisting" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q8" block="b8">
      <answer value="working" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q9" block="b9">
      <answer value="which are often taken" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="which are taken" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q10" block="b10">
      <answer value="introduced" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	Complete each sentence so that it means the same as the sentence before it. Use a relative clause if the first sentence is written with a participle clause, and vice versa.
</header>
	
<section id="body">
  <img class="rightFloat" src="../media/WB_AW_016.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>
  <br/>
  <ol id="questionList">
    <li id="1">Workers involved in decision making are more likely to remain loyal to the company.Workers <input id="q1"/> in decision making are more likely to remain loyal to the company.</li>
    <li id="2">Young people who leave school nowadays are finding it increasingly difficult to find jobs.Young people <input id="q2"/> school nowadays are finding it increasingly difficult to find jobs.</li>
    <li id="3">Only those new businesses filling a real gap in the market can hope to survive.Only those new businesses <input id="q3"/> a real gap in the market can hope to survive.</li>
    <li id="4">Nowadays most people who are looking for work can only expect to be given short-term contracts.Nowadays most people <input id="q4"/> for work can only expect to be given short-term contracts.</li>
    <li id="5">Employees who are offered short-term contracts are likely to suffer from more stress than those with permanent jobs.Employees <input id="q5"/> short-term contracts are likely to suffer from more stress than those with permanent jobs.</li>
    <li id="6">Unemployed people living in big cities have more chance of finding work than those in provincial towns.Unemployed people <input id="q6"/> in big cities have more chance of finding work than those in provincial towns.</li>
    <li id="7">Organisations which consist of fewer layers of management tend to be more efficient.Organisations <input id="q7"/> of fewer layers of management tend to be more efficient.</li>
    <li id="8">Employees who work from home as teleworkers enjoy more freedom to organise their time.Employees <input id="q8"/> from home as teleworkers enjoy more freedom to organise their time.</li>
    <li id="9">Many workers' rights, often taken for granted by employees today, were only gained within the last 100 years.Many workers' rights, <input id="q9"/> for granted by employees today, were only gained within the last 100 years.</li>
    <li id="10">Technology which is introduced in order to improve efficiency in the workplace often has the opposite effect.Technology <input id="q10"/> in order to improve efficiency in the workplace often has the opposite effect.</li>
  </ol>
</section>

</body>
</bento>