<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="gapfill" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-10-31" />
	<meta name="customised" content="false" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking/>
		<feedback groupbased="true" wrongonly="false"/>
		<buttons/>
		<exercise/>
		<misc/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
  <questions>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q1" block="b1">
      <answer value="wider" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q2" block="b2">
      <answer value="more important" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q3" block="b3">
      <answer value="more sedentary" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q4" block="b4">
      <answer value="faster" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q5" block="b5">
      <answer value="not as sociable" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q6" block="b6">
      <answer value="more logical" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q7" block="b7">
      <answer value="not as healthy" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q8" block="b8">
      <answer value="easier" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q9" block="b9">
      <answer value="better-informed" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q10" block="b10">
      <answer value="less creative" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	These comments about the advantages and disadvantages of having a computer at home have been rewritten in a more formal style. Fill each gap with an appropriate comparative structure using one of the adjectives provided.
</header>
	
<section id="noscroll">
</section>

<section id="body">
  <img class="rightFloat" src="../media/LE_AW_015.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>
  <br/>
  <ol id="questionList">
    <li id="1">By using chat and e-mail, it's easier to come into contact with people from all over the world &#x2013; something we couldn't do in the past.Computers allow people to have a <input id="q1"/> social circle than in the past.</li>
    <li id="2">Computer games can be addictive and people who get hooked often stop doing things that are really essential.Some people become addicted to computers and, as a result, they are distracted from doing other, <input id="q2"/> things.</li>
    <li id="3">I've noticed that since I bought my computer I spend far more time sitting down than I used to.Computers have resulted in many people leading a <input id="q3"/> lifestyle.</li>
    <li id="4">My reactions have definitely speeded up since I started playing computer games at home.Computer games give people <input id="q4"/> reactions.</li>
    <li id="5">People spend more time indoors as a result of computers so they don't speak to their neighbours as much.People are <input id="q5"/> as they were in the past.</li>
    <li id="6">I think some computer games are very educational. I'm sure they've improved my son's ability to think logically.Computer games may help people to think in a <input id="q6"/> way.</li>
    <li id="7">I know that some doctors worry that all this sitting in front of computers all day, even in one's free time, is having a really bad effect on people's health.People are <input id="q7"/> as they were in the past as a result of using computers.</li>
    <li id="8">One of the wonderful things about computers and the Internet is that I can exchange information with people all over the world who have the same hobby as me &#x2013; I collect dolls.Having a home computer makes it <input id="q8"/> to exchange information with people all over the world.</li>
    <li id="9">These days you can find information about almost anything on the Web. I think I've really broadened my knowledge about all sorts of things since I've had Internet access from home.For some people, Internet access at home has helped them become <input id="q9"/>.</li>
    <li id="10">Before computer games arrived, children used to spend more of their time building models or painting or inventing stories. They just don't do those things anymore.Children are <input id="q10"/> in their free time than they used to be.</li>
  </ol>
</section>

<section id="rt2001"><p align="left"><font color="#000000">This exercise practises the following comparative structures:</font></p>- Television has become more popular than other leisure activities.- Children today are less imaginative than children in the past.- Children today are not as imaginative as children in the past.- Any invention as pervasive as television is bound to have some harmful effects.At the same time, it will give you ideas for the writing task in the next exercise.
</section>

</body>
</bento>