<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<literals progam="IELTS" version="2.0">
	<language name="English International" code="EN" mediaFolder="EN">
		<group name="group">	
			<lit name="applicationName">Clear Pronunciation</lit>
			<lit name="applicationTitle">Clear Pronunciation</lit>
            
			<lit name="creditLabel">We hope you liked using Clear Pronunciation 1 - Sounds.</lit>
			<lit name="phonemicChartURL"><![CDATA[http://www.clarityenglish.com/Content/ClearPronunciation-International/sharedMedia/phonemicChart.pdf]]></lit>
			<lit name="helpURL"><![CDATA[http://www.clarityenglish.com/Content/ClearPronunciation10-International/help/ClearPronunciationSoundsHelp.pdf]]></lit>
			<lit name="recorderHelpURL"><![CDATA[http://www.clarityenglish.com/Content/ClearPronunciation10-International/help/ClearPronunciationSoundsHelp.pdf]]></lit>
			<lit name="warningWindowCaption">Sorry</lit>
            		<lit name="homeInstructionLabel">Choose the section you want to view.</lit>
			
			<!--  overrides -->
			<lit name="exerciseBackToMenuButton"></lit> <!-- CP doesn't have a label on this button as it is in the icon -->
            		<lit name="recorderButton"></lit> <!-- CP doesn't have a label on this button as it is in the icon -->
			<lit name="exerciseLogOutButton"></lit> <!-- CP doesn't have a label on this button as it is in the icon -->
			
			<!-- Introduction -->
			<lit name="introductionTutorialLabel">Click on an activity below to start.</lit>
			
			<!-- You will -->
			<lit name="introductionYouWillLabel0"><![CDATA[<p>When you have finished this exercise, you will know important vocabulary to help you improve your pronunciation.</p>]]></lit>
			<lit name="introductionYouWillLabel1"><![CDATA[<p>When you have finished this exercise, you will know the names of the parts of the mouth.</p>]]></lit>
			<lit name="introductionYouWillLabel2"><![CDATA[<p>When you have finished this exercise, you will know why it is important to learn the International Phonemic Alphabet.</p>]]></lit>
			<lit name="youWillLabel0"><![CDATA[
			<p>When you have finished this exercise, you should be able to:</p>
			<p>- Recognise each sound when you hear it</p>
			<p>- Pronounce the sounds in different positions in words, for example at the beginning, in the middle or at the end</p>
			<p>- Recognise each phonemic symbol and know which sound it represents.</p>
			]]>
			</lit>
			<lit name="youWillLabel1"><![CDATA[
			<p>When you have finished this exercise, you should be able to hear and pronounce each of the sounds, in words and sentences.</p>
			<p>Extra task: if the sound is at the beginning or end of the word, does it link to the word before or after?</p>
			]]>
			</lit>
			<lit name="youWillLabel2"><![CDATA[
			<p>When you have finished this exercise, you should be confident that you can recognise each of the sounds when you hear them.</p>
			]]></lit>
			<lit name="youWillLabel3"><![CDATA[
			<p>When you have finished this exercise, you should be confident that you can recognise each of the sounds in a real-life situation.</p>
			]]></lit>
			<lit name="youWillLabel4"><![CDATA[
			<p>When you have finished this exercise, you should be confident that you can read the phonemic symbols you will see in a dictionary.</p>
			]]></lit>
			
			<!-- Settings -->
			<lit name="settingsLabel">Choose the channel that plays the video best in your current location.</lit>
			
			<!--unit-->
			<lit name="practiseSoundsLabel"><![CDATA[Practise the sounds]]></lit>
			<lit name="makeSoundsLabel"><![CDATA[How do I make the sounds?]]></lit>
			<lit name="demoTooltipLabel1">Please see Introduction and Consonants, Unit 13 to see the material in this demo.</lit>
			
			<!--phonetic -->
			<lit name="Pill">p</lit>
			<lit name="Fill">f</lit>
			<lit name="Buy">b</lit>
			<lit name="My">m</lit>
			<lit name="Tie">t</lit>
			<lit name="Die">d</lit>
			<lit name="Ship">ʃ</lit>
			<lit name="Chip">tʃ</lit>
			<lit name="Yet">j</lit>
			<lit name="Jet">dʒ</lit>
			<lit name="Game">g</lit>
			<lit name="Came">k</lit>
			<lit name="Wail">w</lit>
			<lit name="Veil">v</lit>
			<lit name="Think">θ</lit>
			<lit name="Sink">s</lit>
			<lit name="There">ð</lit>
			<lit name="Dare">d</lit>
			<lit name="Price">s</lit>
			<lit name="Prize">z</lit>
			<lit name="Asia">ʒ</lit>
			<lit name="Hard">h</lit>
			<lit name="Ran">n</lit>
			<lit name="Rang">ŋ</lit>
			<lit name="Right">r</lit>
			<lit name="Light">l</lit>
			<lit name="Ship2">ɪ</lit>
			<lit name="Sheep">iː</lit>
			<lit name="Head">e</lit>
			<lit name="Had">æ</lit>
			<lit name="Arrive">ə</lit>
			<lit name="Luck">ʌ</lit>
			<lit name="Look">ʊ</lit>
			<lit name="Hat">æ</lit>
			<lit name="Heart">ɑː</lit>
			<lit name="But">ʌ</lit>
			<lit name="Boot">uː</lit>
			<lit name="Who">uː</lit>
			<lit name="Her">ɜː</lit>
			<lit name="Pot">ɒ</lit>
			<lit name="Port">ɔː</lit>
			<lit name="Hair">eə</lit>
			<lit name="Hear">ɪə</lit>
			<lit name="Pay">eɪ</lit>
			<lit name="Pie">aɪ</lit>
			<lit name="Boy">ɔɪ</lit>
			<lit name="Buy2">aɪ</lit>
			<lit name="Know">əʊ</lit>
			<lit name="Now">aʊ</lit>

			<!--Animation instruction-->
			<lit name="instructionLabel">Click on the IPA symbol to play the animation.</lit>
			<lit name="redArrowTitleLabel">voiced sound:</lit>
			<lit name="redArrowLabel">use your vocal cords</lit>
			<lit name="yellowArrowTileLabel">unvoiced sound:</lit>
			<lit name="yellowArrowLabel">don't use your vocal cords</lit>
            <lit name="tabletAnimationAlertLabel">Sorry. This animation will not run on your tablet. Please use a computer to view it.</lit>
			<lit name="PillInstruction"><![CDATA[At first your teeth are slightly apart, with the front of your tongue down, and your lips together. Your lips are stopping the air coming out. When you open your lips, you release the air.{newline}/{ipa}/ is unvoiced, so you don't use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="FillInstruction"><![CDATA[Your bottom lip moves upwards to touch your top teeth. The soft part at the back of the roof of your mouth rises. As you make the sound, the air comes out of your mouth and the middle of your tongue moves down.{newline}/{ipa}/ is unvoiced, so you don't use your vocal cords.]]></lit>>
			<lit name="VeilInstruction"><![CDATA[Your bottom lip moves upwards to touch your top teeth. The soft part at the back of the roof of your mouth rises. As you make the sound, the air comes out of your mouth and the middle of your tongue moves down.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="WailInstruction"><![CDATA[Your tongue is very high at the back, with the sides touching the roof of your mouth. It is very low at the front, with the tip touching below the teeth. Your lips are rounded as the air passes through them.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="RanInstruction"><![CDATA[The front of your tongue moves up so that it touches the roof of your mouth. At the same time you make a noise with your vocal cords. The air comes out of your nose, rather than your mouth.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="RangInstruction"><![CDATA[The middle of your tongue moves up so that it touches the roof of your mouth. At the same time you make a noise with your vocal cords. The air comes out of your nose, rather than your mouth.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="TieInstruction"><![CDATA[At first, the front of your tongue is against the roof of your mouth, with the sides of your tongue against your teeth. Your tongue is stopping the air coming out. When you pull the front of your tongue down, you release the air.{newline}/{ipa}/ is unvoiced, so you don't use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="SinkInstruction"><![CDATA[The front of your tongue moves forward to your bottom teeth. The sides of your tongue are against your teeth. Your lips are open. The air comes out over your tongue and between your teeth.{newline}/{ipa}/ is unvoiced, so you don't use your vocal cords.]]></lit>			
			<lit name="DieInstruction"><![CDATA[At first, the front of your tongue is against the roof of your mouth, with the sides of your tongue against your teeth.  Your tongue is stopping the air coming out. When you pull the front of your tongue down, you release the air.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="PriceInstruction"><![CDATA[The front of your tongue moves forward to your bottom teeth. The sides of your tongue are against your teeth. Your lips are open. The air comes out over your tongue and between your teeth.{newline}/{ipa}/ is unvoiced, so you don't use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="PrizeInstruction"><![CDATA[The front of your tongue moves forward to your bottom teeth. The sides of your tongue are against your teeth. Your lips are open. The air comes out over your tongue and between your teeth.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="RightInstruction"><![CDATA[Your teeth are slightly apart. As you make the sound, your tongue pulls back, so that the sides are against your teeth. The front of your tongue moves up slightly. As you make the sound, the corners of your lips move inwards slightly, pushing the front of your lips out.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="LightInstruction"><![CDATA[The front of your tongue moves up to the roof of your mouth, and the sides of your tongue move away from your teeth. As you make the sound, the air passes over your tongue, and between your tongue and your teeth.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="ThinkInstruction"><![CDATA[As you open your mouth slightly, the front of your tongue moves between your teeth. The air comes out between your tongue and your teeth. As you make the sound, the back of your mouth rises slightly.{newline}/{ipa}/ is unvoiced, so you don't use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="ThereInstruction"><![CDATA[As you open your mouth slightly, the front of your tongue moves between your teeth. The air comes out between your tongue and your teeth. As you make the sound, the back of your mouth rises slightly.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="YetInstruction"><![CDATA[The front of your tongue is behind your bottom teeth. As you make the sound, the back of your tongue moves upwards and the sides press against the roof of your mouth. The front of your tongue moves down as your throat releases the air.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords. ]]></lit>
			<lit name="JetInstruction"><![CDATA[The front of your tongue moves to the roof of your mouth and the sides of your tongue push against your teeth.  Your tongue stops the air coming out. When you pull the front of your tongue down, you release the air in a stream.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="ChipInstruction"><![CDATA[At first the front of your tongue is against the roof of your mouth with the sides against your teeth. Your tongue stops the air coming out. When you pull the front of your tongue down, you release the air in a stream.{newline}/{ipa}/ is unvoiced, so you don't use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="CameInstruction"><![CDATA[At first the back of your tongue is against the roof of your mouth with the sides of your tongue push against your teeth.  Your tongue is stopping the air coming out. When you pull the back of your tongue down, you release the air.{newline}/{ipa}/ is unvoiced, so you don't use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="GameInstruction"><![CDATA[At first your teeth are slightly apart with the back of your tongue against the roof of your mouth and the sides of your tongue against your teeth. Your lips are slightly open. Your tongue is stopping the air coming out. When you pull the back of your tongue down, you release the air.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="BuyInstruction"><![CDATA[At first, your teeth are slightly apart with the front of your tongue down and your lips together. Your lips are stopping the air coming out. When you open your lips, you release the air.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="Buy2Instruction"><![CDATA[First, the front of your toungue pushes down against your bottom teeth. Then it moves backwards and the back of your tongue moves up. As the air comes out, your lips move sideways slightly.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="MyInstruction"><![CDATA[Close your mouth and push your lips together slightly, with your tongue pressing down. As you do this, make a sound using your vocal cords. The sound comes out of your nose rather than your mouth.]]></lit>
			<lit name="ShipInstruction"><![CDATA[At first, your teeth are slightly apart, with the sides of your tongue resting against your top teeth. As you start to make the sound, your tongue pulls back slightly, and the front of your tongue moves up.{newline}/{ipa}/ is unvoiced, so you don't use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="AsiaInstruction"><![CDATA[The sides of your tongue rest against your top teeth. As you start to make the sound, your tongue pulls back slightly, and the front of your tongue moves up.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="HardInstruction"><![CDATA[Your mouth is open. As you make the sound, the back of your tongue moves up slightly. Air passes over your tongue, through your mouth, and out.{newline}/{ipa}/ is unvoiced, so you don't use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="Ship2Instruction"><![CDATA[Your tongue is flat, with the sides between your teeth. The front of your tongue moves forwards to touch your bottom teeth. As the air comes out, your lips move sideways slightly.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="SheepInstruction"><![CDATA[Your tongue is flat with the sides between your teeth. The front of your tongue moves forwards to touch your bottom teeth, and the middle rises towards the front of your mouth. Your lips move sideways slightly.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, and is a longer sound than /{compareipa}/.]]></lit>
			<lit name="HatInstruction"><![CDATA[As you make this sound your lips pull down at the corners. The front of your tongue presses against the back of your bottom teeth, and the middle of your tongue moves down slightly.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="HeartInstruction"><![CDATA[As you make this sound your mouth opens. The front of your tongue pulls down to below your bottom teeth, and the middle of your tongue moves up. The sound comes from the back of your mouth.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, and is a longer sound than /{compareipa}/.]]></lit>
			<lit name="PotInstruction"><![CDATA[The front of your tongue pulls back. The middle of your tongue pulls down and the back of your tongue moves up as you make the sound.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="PortInstruction"><![CDATA[The front of your tongue pulls back almost as far as it will go. The middle of your tongue pulls down and the back of your tongue moves up as you make the sound.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="HeadInstruction"><![CDATA[As you make this sound your lips pull down at the corners. The front of your tongue moves forwards and presses against the back of your bottom teeth.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="HadInstruction"><![CDATA[As you make this sound your lips pull down at the corners. The front of your tongue presses against the back of your bottom teeth, and the middle of your tongue moves down slightly.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="ButInstruction"><![CDATA[As you make this sound your lips pull down at the corners. The front of your tongue presses against the back of your bottom teeth, and pulls backwards as the back of your tongue rises.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="BootInstruction"><![CDATA[As you make this sound, your lips push together in a circle. The back of your tongue pushes up.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords. The ː in the symbol for this sound shows that it is slightly longer.]]></lit>
			<lit name="WhoInstruction"><![CDATA[As you make this sound, your lips push together in a circle. The back of your tongue pushes up.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords. The ː in the symbol for this sound shows that it is slightly longer.]]></lit>
			<lit name="HerInstruction"><![CDATA[As you make the sound, the middle of your tongue moves down with the sides against your teeth. The back of your tongue pulls up slightly.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="DareInstruction"><![CDATA[At first, the front of your tongue is against the roof of your mouth, with the sides of your tongue against your teeth.  Your tongue is stopping the air coming out. When you pull the front of your tongue down, you release the air.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="NowInstruction"><![CDATA[First, your tongue pulls back so that the sides are between your back teeth, and the back of your tongue is raised with the front down. The corners of your lips move apart. Then the front of your tongue pulls back and your lips come together in a small circle. ]]></lit>
			<lit name="KnowInstruction"><![CDATA[Your tongue and lips relax and the air passes over your tongue. Then the back of your tongue moves up, pulling the front of your tongue back. At the same time, the corners of your lips pull in, pushing the middle part of your lips out.]]></lit>
			<lit name="PayInstruction"><![CDATA[First, your lips pull down at the corners and the front of your tongue presses against the back of your bottom teeth. Then the middle of your tongue moves up. As the air comes out, your lips move sideways slightly.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="PieInstruction"><![CDATA[First, the front of your tongue pushes down against your bottom teeth. Then it moves backwards and the back of your tongue moves up. As the air comes out, your lips move sideways slightly.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="HairInstruction"><![CDATA[First, your lips pull down at the corners, and the front of your tongue presses forwards against the back of your bottom teeth. Then the middle of your tongue pulls up as the air passes over your tongue.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="HearInstruction"><![CDATA[Your tongue is flat with the sides between your teeth. The front of your tongue moves forwards to touch your bottom teeth, and the middle of your tongue rises towards the front of your mouth. Then your tongue and lips relax and the air passes over your tongue.]]></lit>
			<lit name="BoyInstruction"><![CDATA[First, your lips push forward into a circle. The front of your tongue starts against your bottom teeth and then pulls back. The middle of your tongue pushes up and forwards. As the air comes out, your tongue rises towards the front of your mouth. ]]></lit>
			<lit name="ArriveInstruction"><![CDATA[Your tongue and lips are relaxed. As you make the sound, your mouth opens slightly and the air passes over your tongue.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
			<lit name="LuckInstruction"><![CDATA[As you make this sound your lips pull down at the corners. The front of your tongue presses against the back of your bottom teeth, and pulls backwards as the back of your tongue rises.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>
            <lit name="LookInstruction"><![CDATA[The back of your tongue moves up slightly, pulling the front of your tongue back. At the same time, the corners of your lips pull in, pushing the middle part of your lips out.{newline}/{ipa}/ is voiced, so you use your vocal cords.]]></lit>

		</group>
	</language>
</literals>