<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tips>
	<tip id="1" type="Teachers">
	<![CDATA[
		<p>
			From Simon Cockell, Sultan Qaboos University<br/>
			It is very important to provide an overview of the data in Task 1. If you don't, you will lose marks. To practise this, look at graphs online and give them an overview statement. For example, "This graph shows the most popular Asian countries for tourists, and the months in which they visit these countries."
		</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="2" type="Teachers">
<![CDATA[
		<p>From Kevin McLaven, British Council <br/> Join with friends to practise Part Two of the Speaking test, the 1-2 minute talk. Each person writes a topic on paper, folds it and puts it in a bowl. One by one, pick a topic from the bowl and talk about it for two minutes. Ask each other follow-up questions at the end.
</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="3" type="Teachers">
<![CDATA[
		<p>From Marc Lebane, Lingnan University <br/> Rather than starting to write immediately, you should brainstorm ideas and then organise your thoughts into paragraphs. If you use the first few minutes of test time to think and plan, it will save you time and will probably improve your score.
</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="4" type="Teachers">
<![CDATA[
		<p>From Steve Maginn, author <br/> Questions are usually in the same order as the answers in the text. So, the answer to Question 1 will be earlier in the text than that for Question 2. Use answers you have found to locate the answers to questions you are unsure of. If you have the answers to questions 1 and 3, the answer to question 2 should be in between.
</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="5" type="Teachers">
<![CDATA[
		<p>From Greg Selby, British Council <br/> Become familiar with question types and task types in each of the four skill tests. If you do nothing else, you really must do this. It will take the stress out of the experience and save you time in the test. Get started with Road to IELTS (http://www.roadtoielts.com/testdrive/)
</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="6" type="Teachers">
<![CDATA[
		<p>From Simon Cockell, Sultan Qaboos University <br/> It is very important to provide an overview of the data in Task 1. If you don't, you will lose marks. To practise this, look at graphs online and give them an overview statement. For example, "This graph shows the most popular Asian countries for tourists, and the months in which they visit these countries."
</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="7" type="Candidates">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Take one or two mock tests before the real test. Create an environment almost exactly the same as the one in which the real test will be developed. Go into a quiet room, remove all distractions and time yourself. This strategy aims to measure yourself under "real conditions". This way, you will be able to analyse your mistakes and the things you do well.</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="8" type="Reading">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Have a wide vocabulary, recognising words with the same or similar meanings words with opposite meanings. Expand your vocabulary by learning ten words a day; learn them in groups of word groups (e.g. university, academic, student, lecture, etc.)</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="9" type="Reading">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Follow the instructions. "No more than three words" means no more than three words. "One or two words" means one or two words. Not following the instructions suggests you do not understand the question; you will lose marks.</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="10" type="Listening">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Make notes on your response sheet if you are unsure of what they say. You can guess at an answer later. You do not get penalised for having the wrong answer - it is better to guess if you are unsure than to leave an answer blank. This applies to the Reading section too. Leaving spaces can also get you into trouble as you might write a correct answer in the wrong place later.</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="11" type="Speaking">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Speak clearly and confidently. The examiner is not testing your knowledge. They are testing your ability to make a point and expand on it. Elaborate on your point. Use connecting words like 'also' or 'however' and phrases like 'on a similar note' and 'on the other hand'.</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="12" type="Speaking">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Talk to the examiner (not the recorder!) and link your sentences and ideas clearly so there is a nice flow from one sentence or idea to the next. Don't leave your manners at home! Greet the examiner, maybe ask how they're doing then say thanks and goodbye before you leave.</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="13" type="Speaking">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Use correct tenses. "Did you play sports as a child?" "Yes, I did." "Do you play sports?" "Yes, I do." For some quick revision of your basic tenses, try Tense Buster at (suitable link here).</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="14" type="Speaking">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Don't be afraid to ask the examiner to repeat the question if you didn't hear it or don't understand it. You are more likely to lose marks for not answering the right question than for asking for clarification</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="15" type="Speaking">
<![CDATA[
		<p>If you get "lost" when speaking, don't be afraid to start again. Take a deep breath and say something like, "Sorry, what I mean to say is..." </p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="16" type="Preparation">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Improve your vocabulary. Read articles and underline words. Learn the words in sentences. Practise speaking them and writing them. Use them in your daily conversations. Get started with articles from the BBC (www.bbc.com) or CNN (www.cnn.com).</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="17" type="Preparation">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Are you aware of what you can and cannot ask the invigilator during the test? If you don't understand what to do, think you do not have all the correct materials or cannot hear the audio, you can ask the invigilator for assistance. You cannot ask for assistance if you don't understand the question. Familiarise yourself with question types with Road to IELTS (http://www.roadtoielts.com/testdrive/)</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="18" type="Preparation">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Create your own proofreading checklist so you know what to look for when you have completed your writing. If you think your tense usage is poor, you want to include tenses. Other common things to look for: spelling, capitalisation, using paragraphs, and punctuation. Do not limit yourself to just these though.</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="19" type="Preparation">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Try to learn from other students who have already done the IELTS test. You can ask your friends about their experience. This will help to be prepared for situations which are not listed in study books. You will feel more comfortable knowing what other candidates knew. You'll realise you don't need to be superman or superwoman to get the score you want.</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="20" type="Preparation">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Get into the right frame of mind before the exam starts. Be ready to work. Go to the washroom beforehand; five minutes out can mean missing out on important time and information towards the end. Some candidates have to learn this the hard way; now you don't!</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="21" type="Preparation">
<![CDATA[
		<p>One of the best ways to learn what you have to do in both the Writing and Speaking tests is by checking band score descriptors from reliable sources online. The British Council's list of band score descriptors is available at http://takeielts.britishcouncil.org/find-out-about-results/ielts-assessment-criteria</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="22" type="Preparation">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Computers have made it easy for us to neglect small mistakes, like spelling and homonyms (words that sound the same but have different meanings, most commonly: there, they're and their or to, too and two. Small mistakes can cost you big marks if you make too many of them. Practise your spelling and make sure you are using the right words.  </p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="23" type="Speaking">
<![CDATA[
		<p>When you are practising for Part Two of the Speaking test, record yourself. Play it back and listen for areas you can improve. Perhaps you speak too quickly or too slowly; maybe your pronunciation could use improvement. Have a list of things to talk about: a person, a book, a holiday, a hobby. Talk about these things for one to two minutes each. Recording your voice also lets you see how you have improved over time. Looking for a recorder? Download and try the easy-to-use Clarity Recorder (http://www.clarityenglish.com/resources/recorder.php)</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="24" type="Listening">
<![CDATA[
		<p>Make listening the core of your practice. A good listener is a good communicator. The more we hear, the more we can speak. The more we can speak, the more we can read and articulate in writing. (Include link to listening material online?)</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="25" type="Writing">
<![CDATA[
		<p>TBC</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="26" type="Writing">
<![CDATA[
		<p>TBC</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="27" type="Reading">
<![CDATA[
		<p>TBC</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="28" type="Listening">
<![CDATA[
		<p>TBC</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="29" type="Writing">
<![CDATA[
		<p>TBC</p>
	]]>
	</tip>

	<tip id="30" type="Reading">
<![CDATA[
		<p>TBC</p>
	]]>
	</tip>
	
	<tip id="31" type="Listening">
<![CDATA[
		<p>TBC</p>
	]]>
	</tip>
</tips>