<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion" type="targetspotting" date="2011-10-25" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[			
		list {
			list-style-type: decimal;
			margin-left: 0; 
			padding-left: 20px; 
			padding-bottom: 12px; 
		}
		p {
			padding-bottom: 12px; 
		}
		.no-padding {
			padding-bottom: 0px; 
		}
		.h1 {
			font-size: 12px;
			font-weight: bold;
			color: #3A00FF;	
		}
		#noscroll span[draggable="true"] {
		   float: left;
		   width: 140px;
		} 
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking instant="true"/>
		<feedback neutral="true"/>
		<buttons feedback="false" marking="false"/>
		<exercise/>
		<misc/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<questions><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="q1" correct="false"><feedback source="fb1"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="q2" correct="false"><feedback source="fb2"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="q3" correct="false"><feedback source="fb3"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="q4" correct="false"><feedback source="fb4"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion></questions></script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	What will I learn in this unit?
</header>
	
<section id="body">
	<img class="rightFloat" src="../Media/SS_AR_001.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"  /><p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Academic Reading Passage 1</b></font>Bands, Tribes and ChiefdomsRead a book extract comparing the main characteristics of bands, tribes and chiefdoms.</p><p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Academic Reading Passage 2</b></font>HypermobilityRead an article discussing the effects of modern means of transport and communications on society.</p><p align="left"><b>Question types</b>You will attempt four question types.<u><g id="1">Classification</g></u><u><g id="2">Matching (sentence beginnings and endings)</g></u><u><g id="3">Yes, No, Not Given</g></u><u><g id="4">Short-answer questions</g></u></p><p align="left"><font size="2"></font></p>
</section>
<section id="fb1">
	<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">
		<b>Classification</b></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">This is similar to the matching exercise, with the difference that you are not making one-to-one matches, but grouping pieces of information, names or other details into categories or classifications.</font></p>
		<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p>
		<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Read the instructions carefully and make sure you know which letters represent each category. Remember that some categories are a combination of two other categories in the same exercise. For example, 'Painting', 'Sculpture' and 'Both Painting and Sculpture' could be three possible categories. Similarly, a category can exclude all others in the exercise. For example 'Neither Painting nor Sculpture' is a possible category.</font></p>
		<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p>
		<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Next, read the list of statements carefully. For each one, underline key words and decide which part of the text is likely to give the answer by looking for the same words or words which mean the same in the text. Remember that the questions in this exercise do not follow the order of the text, so you will have to keep moving about the text to locate information. With some statements, you may need to skim the text to find information from different parts. This is especially true of the combination categories mentioned earlier. Once you think you have found the relevant sentence, read it and the sentence immediately before and after it.</font></p>
		<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p>
		<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Make sure that at the end of the exercise you have used all the categories at least once. If this isn't the case, you've probably made a mistake.</font></p>
</section>
<section id="fb2">
	<p align="left"><b>Matching sentence beginnings to endings or matching cause and effect</b></p><p align="left"></p><p align="left"><font color="#000000">In many ways, these exercise types are similar to multiple choice questions. Exercises typically consist of the first half of a series of statements with a number of possible outcomes or endings to choose from. In some cases the questions may have a common theme – such as matching a cause to an effect in order to make the whole sentence.</font></p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">As with multiple choice questions you shouldn't search through the text until you have compared the alternatives carefully and are clear on how the options are different. Before you start to look for the answers, you should also make sure you read all the sentence beginnings and all the options.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left"><font color="#000000">Be careful – some distractors in the options might be synonyms (words that mean the same thing) with words in the text, but you shouldn't assume that this is the correct answer. You need to consider the meaning of the whole sentence, not just individual words.</font></p>
</section>
<section id="fb3">
	<p align="left"><b>Yes/No/Not Given</b></p><p align="left"><font color="#000000">(Writer's views/opinions/claims)</font></p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">At least one of the three texts in the reading test will include detailed logical argument, where the writer expresses views on a certain issue or explains and discusses views held by others. Yes/No/Not Given is the most likely exercise type with texts like this. This exercise tests how well you can identify and understand views or claims in the text.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">You are given a list of statements and asked whether they agree with or contradict the opinions of the writer, or if no opinion is expressed concerning this issue. As with all exercises that focus on a particular detail of the text, the first thing you should do is identify which section of the text each question refers to. Once you've found the right part of the text, read through the relevant paragraph carefully.</p>
</section>
<section id="fb4">
	<p align="left"><b>Short Answer Questions</b></p><p align="left"><font color="#000000">(Discrete questions and 'listing' questions)</font></p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">These questions test how well you can find specific pieces of information in the text. Question words such as 'who', 'where' and 'when' will help you understand what kind of information you are looking for. If you have already skimmed over the text, you should know which part of the text will give you your answer, so you can go directly to the relevant section.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Make sure you read the instructions very carefully, because you will usually be asked to take a certain number of words directly from the text. If this is the case, make sure you don't go over the word limit, which is usually three words, and don't change the words from the text in any way. You shouldn't have to use contractions in your answer, so if your answer includes them, it's probably wrong. Also, watch your spelling. Candidates often lose marks because they are careless when they copy words from the text.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Sometimes you will be asked to list a number of items or examples mentioned in the text. Usually you can list them in any order, but read the instructions carefully to make sure this is the case.</p>
</section>
</body>
</bento>