<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion" type="targetspotting" date="2011-10-27" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking instant="true"/>
		<feedback neutral="true"/>
		<buttons feedback="false" marking="false"/>
		<exercise/>
		<misc/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<questions><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="t1" correct="false"><feedback source="fb1"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="t2" correct="false"><feedback source="fb2"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion></questions></script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	What will I learn in this unit?
</header>
	
<section id="body">
	<img class="rightFloat" src="../media/EN_LN_001.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"  /><p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Conversation (social context)</b></font></p>You will&#160;listen to a conversation about adopting a zoo animal.<p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Conversation (educational context) </b></font></p>You will&#160;listen to a lecture about the structure of the Earth.<p align="left"><font color="#000000"><b>Question types:</b>&#160;</font></p>You will attempt two question types.<u><g id="t1">Form Completion</g></u><u><g id="t2">Labelling a Diagram</g></u><p align="left"><font size="2"></font></p>
</section>
<section id="fb1">
	<p align="left"><b>Form Completion</b></p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">You are usually given a form that needs to be filled in with personal details or other factual information using information from the listening text.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Read the instructions carefully. They will usually state that your answer should be NO MORE THAN THREE WORDS OR A NUMBER. But check this is the case.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Read through the form and decide what you need to listen for. Forms will often require details like names and addresses. Take note of any headings.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">You may be able to predict one or two of the answers.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Complete the form as you listen. The information will be given in the same order as the spaces in the form.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Use the words you hear, not your own.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Remember as you write, the answer could be a number, one word, two words or three words but not four words or more.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">If you think you need more than three words your answer is probably incorrect.</p>
</section>
<section id="fb2">
	<p align="left"><b>Labelling a Diagram</b></p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">You will be given a diagram and asked to label it with labels given in the listening text. Sometimes you may be given a box of words or phrases from which to select the labels.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Read the instructions carefully. They will state how many words you should use if there is not a box of labels provided. You could be asked to write one word only.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Study the diagram.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">You may be able to predict one or two answers or associated vocabulary that you may hear connected to a particular label.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Check whether the labels are numbered in a clockwise or anticlockwise direction.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">The information will be given in the same order as the numbers on the diagram.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Write down or select the labels as you listen.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Use the words you hear, not your own.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Remember to listen carefully when words are spelt out. Write them down even if you don't know where they go.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Use the information given on the diagram to help you if you get lost.</p>
</section>
</body>
</bento>