<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion" type="gapfill" date="2011-10-27" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking/>
		<feedback wrongonly="false"/>
		<buttons/>
		<exercise samelengthgaps="true"/>
		<misc/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<questions><GapFillQuestion source="q1"><answer value="whose " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q2"><answer value="which " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q3"><answer value="which " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q4"><answer value="which " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q5"><answer value="who " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q6"><answer value="whose " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion></questions></script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	Relative clauses can be used to make one sentence from two. In each case below, complete the sentence by adding the relative pronoun.
</header>
	
<section id="body">
	<img class="rightFloat" src="../media/EN_AW_005.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"  /><p align="left"><b>1.</b>The water-balanced railway's hydraulic brake helps store energy to pump water. Its main function is to slow the train.&#160;The water-balanced railway's hydraulic brake <input id="q1" /> main function is to slow the train, helps store energy to pump water.</p><p align="left"><b>2.</b>A solar cell is a power source. It converts sunlight into electricity.A solar cell is a power source <input id="q2" /> converts sunlight into electricity.</p><p align="left"><b>3.</b>A hydram is powered by water pressure. It can irrigate fields 60 metres above the water source.A hydram,&#160;<input id="q3" /> can irrigate fields sixty metres above the water source, is powered by water pressure.</p><p align="left"><b>4.</b>The water-balanced railway is an example of sustainable technology. It is powered by the force of gravity.The water-balanced railway,&#160;<input id="q4" /> is powered by the force of gravity, is an example of sustainable technology.</p><p align="left"><b>5.</b>Ecologists are scientists. They study the relationship between living organisms and their environment.Ecologists are scientists&#160;<input id="q5" /> study the relationship between living organisms and their environment.</p><p align="left"><b>6.</b>Greenpeace is an organisation. Its aim is to protect wildlife and the natural environment.Greenpeace is an organisation&#160;<input id="q6" /> aim is to protect wildlife and the natural environment.</p><p align="left"><font size="2"></font></p>
</section>
<section id="rt2001">
	<p align="left"><font color="#000000">When describing an object we often use relative clauses to give information about its function, construction and so on. These may be defining relative clauses, for example:</font></p>&nbsp;A ballast tank is a tank which holds water for weight.&nbsp;The relative clause gives essential information about the object, so it is a defining relative clause.&nbsp;Or they may be non-defining relative clauses, for example:&nbsp;The carriages, which can carry up to 20 passengers, go up and down a steep slope.&nbsp;The relative clause gives additional information about the object, so it is a non-defining relative clause. Only non-defining relative clauses need to be enclosed in commas.
</section>
</body>
</bento>