<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion" type="targetspotting" date="2011-09-28" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[			
		list {
			list-style-type: decimal;
			margin-left: 0; 
			padding-left: 20px; 
			padding-bottom: 12px; 
		}
		p {
			padding-bottom: 12px; 
		}
		.no-padding {
			padding-bottom: 0px; 
		}
		.h1 {
			font-size: 12px;
			font-weight: bold;
			color: #3A00FF;	
		}
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking instant="true"/>
		<feedback neutral="true"/>
		<buttons feedback="false" marking="false"/>
		<exercise/>
		<misc/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	

<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<questions><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="1" correct="false"><feedback source="1"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="2" correct="false"><feedback source="2"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion></questions></script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	What will I learn in this unit?
</header>
	
<section id="body">
	<p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Monologue (social context)</b></font></p>You will listen to a talk about places to eat out in a town.<p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Conversation (educational context)</b></font></p>You will listen to two students talking about a survey on popular forms of physical activity.<p align="left"><b>Question types</b>You will attempt two question types.<u><g id="1">Short answer questions</g></u><u><g id="2">Table completion</g></u></p><p align="left"><font size="2"></font></p><img class="rightFloat" src="../Media/LE_LN_001.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"  />
</section>
<section id="fb1">
	<p align="left"><b>Short Answers</b></p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">These are questions requiring general information or specific details which you will find by listening to the text. You will be given a question and a space for your answer.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Read the instructions carefully. They will usually state that your answer should be NO MORE THAN THREE WORDS. But check this is the case.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Read through all the questions.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Underline the key words in the questions.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Decide what kind of information you are listening for. Look out for question words like 'where' and 'who' which indicate you should listen out for specific things like places and people.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">You may be able to predict one or two of the answers.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">If you don't know the meaning of any of the words in the questions look at the other questions. They might have some associated vocabulary in them to help you guess the meaning.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Answer the questions as you listen.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">The information will be given in the same order as the questions although it may be expressed differently.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">You may use your own words.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Remember as you write, the answer could be one word, two words or three words but not four words or more.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">If you think you need more than three words your answer is probably wrong.</p>
</section>
<section id="fb2">
	<p align="left"><b>Notes/Table Completion</b></p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">These questions ask for specific information. You may be given incomplete notes or a table with spaces to fill using information from the listening text.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Read the instructions carefully. They will usually state that your answer should be NO MORE THAN THREE WORDS OR A NUMBER. But check this is the case.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Read through the notes or table and decide what you need to listen for. Take note of any headings. They will give you a good indication of what the text will be about.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">You may be able to predict one or two of the answers.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Check whether the questions or spaces are arranged vertically or horizontally.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Complete the notes or table as you listen. The information will be given in the same order as the spaces in the notes or table. </p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Use the words you hear, not your own.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Remember as you write, the answer could be a number, one word, two words or three words but not four words or more.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">If you think you need more than three words your answer is probably incorrect.</p>
</section>
</body>
</bento>