<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion" type="targetspotting" date="2011-09-29" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[			
		list {
			list-style-type: decimal;
			margin-left: 0; 
			padding-left: 20px; 
			padding-bottom: 12px; 
		}
		p {
			padding-bottom: 12px; 
		}
		.no-padding {
			padding-bottom: 0px; 
		}
		.h1 {
			font-size: 12px;
			font-weight: bold;
			color: #3A00FF;	
		}
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking instant="true"/>
		<feedback neutral="true"/>
		<buttons feedback="false" marking="false"/>
		<exercise/>
		<misc/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<questions><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="1" correct="false"><feedback source="1"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion><TargetSpottingQuestion><answer source="2" correct="false"><feedback source="2"/></answer></TargetSpottingQuestion></questions></script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	What will I learn in this unit?
</header>
	
<section id="body">
	<p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Board games</b></font>You will read an article about the history of board games.</p><p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Pastimes and games of native peoples</b></font>You will read an article about games played by indigenous people in various parts of the world.</p><p align="left"><b>Question types</b>You will attempt two question types.<u><g id="1">Short answer questions</g></u><u><g id="2">Table completion</g></u></p><p align="left"><font size="2"></font></p><img class="rightFloat" src="../Media/LE_AR_001.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"  />
</section>
<section id="fb1">
	<p align="left"><b>Short Answer Questions</b></p><p align="left"><font color="#000000">(Discrete questions and 'listing' questions)</font></p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">These questions test how well you can find specific pieces of information in the text. Question words such as 'who', 'where' and 'when' will help you understand what kind of information you are looking for. If you have already skimmed over the text, you should know which part of the text will give you your answer, so you can go directly to the relevant section.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Make sure you read the instructions very carefully, because you will usually be asked to take a certain number of words directly from the text. If this is the case, make sure you don't go over the word limit, which is usually three words, and don't change the words from the text in any way. You shouldn't have to use contractions in your answer, so if your answer includes them, it's probably wrong. Also, watch your spelling. Candidates often lose marks because they are careless when they copy words from the text.</p><p align="left"></p><p align="left">Sometimes you will be asked to list a number of items or examples mentioned in the text. Usually you can list them in any order, but read the instructions carefully to make sure this is the case.</p>
</section>
<section id="fb2">
	<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"><b>Table Completion</b></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">(Gaps are NOT part of sentences)</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">This is an exercise which checks how quickly and accurately you can find specific pieces of information in the text. The table you have to complete will summarise certain parts of the passage. In some cases all the information will be found in the same section of the text. Sometimes information for each column or row may come from different sections. If you have already skimmed over the text, you should know which part will give you your answer, so you can go directly to the relevant section.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Before you search for your answers, take time to understand how the table is organised. Look at column and row headings, so that you know what kind of information is required. The information in the text is presented in the same order as the numbered gaps in the table and knowing this should help you find your answers.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000"></font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">As with all exercise types, don't forget to read the instructions carefully. Usually, your answer should be no more than three words or a number.</font></p>
</section>
</body>
</bento>