<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="multiplechoice" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-11-14" />
	<meta name="customised" content="true" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen.css" type="text/css" media="screen" />
<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen-print.css" type="text/css" media="print" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	
	
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<popups>
    	<popup click="clickme" source="examtips" width="500" />
	</popups>
<settings>
 	<param name="delayedMarking" value="true" />
</settings>
  <questions>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q1">
      <answer source="a1" correct="true">
        <feedback source="fb1"/>
      </answer>
      <answer source="a2" correct="false">
        <feedback source="fb1"/>
      </answer>
      <answer source="a3" correct="false">
        <feedback source="fb1"/>
      </answer>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q2">
      <answer source="a4" correct="false">
        <feedback source="fb2"/>
      </answer>
      <answer source="a5" correct="true">
        <feedback source="fb2"/>
      </answer>
      <answer source="a6" correct="false">
	          <feedback source="fb2"/>
      </answer>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q3">
      <answer source="a7" correct="true">
	          <feedback source="fb3"/>
      </answer>
      <answer source="a8" correct="false">
	          <feedback source="fb3"/>
      </answer>
      <answer source="a9" correct="false">
	          <feedback source="fb3"/>
      </answer>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q4">
      <answer source="a10" correct="false">
	          <feedback source="fb4"/>
      </answer>
      <answer source="a11" correct="true">
	          <feedback source="fb4"/>
      </answer>
      <answer source="a12" correct="false">
	          <feedback source="fb4"/>
      </answer>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q5">
      <answer source="a13" correct="false">
	          <feedback source="fb5"/>
      </answer>
      <answer source="a14" correct="false">
	          <feedback source="fb5"/>
      </answer>
      <answer source="a15" correct="true">
	          <feedback source="fb5"/>
      </answer>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q6">
      <answer source="a16" correct="true">
	  	  <feedback source="fb6"/>
	  	  </answer>
      <answer source="a17" correct="false">
	  	  	  <feedback source="fb6"/>
	  	  </answer>
      <answer source="a18" correct="false">
	  <feedback source="fb6"/>
	  	  </answer>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q7">
      <answer source="a19" correct="false">
	  	  <feedback source="fb7"/>
	  </answer>
      <answer source="a20" correct="false">
	  	  <feedback source="fb7"/>
	  </answer>
      <answer source="a21" correct="true">
	  <feedback source="fb7"/>
	  </answer>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	
		<div id="instruction">
		Read this sample answer to the last Writing Task on the left and complete it by choosing the clause or phrase which best fits each gap.
		</div>
</header>
	


<section id="readingText">
<a id="clickme"><img class="imagetask" src="../media/btn_examtips.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/></a><br/><br/>
  <p>
    The tradition which some countries have of free admission to state-owned museums is coming under increasing threat due to rising costs and limited funding. Despite these pressures, many museums in these countries &#xA0;<b>(1)</b>.
  </p>
  <p>
    There are several advantages to allowing the public free access to museums. Firstly, whereas charging an entry fee means that a nation's heritage is only available to those who can afford it,&#xA0; <b>(2)</b>. As a result, museums, like public libraries, are treated as an extension of the state education system, which is based on the principle of equal opportunity for all. A further advantage is that free museums attract far more visitors because, although many people make a special trip to visit them,&#xA0; <b>(3)</b>. Free museums, therefore, reach a much wider public. Finally, while private museums may be influenced by commercial pressures,&#xA0; <b>(4)</b>.
  </p>
  <p>
    However, a policy of free admission to museums also has a number of disadvantages. First and foremost, museums whose income comes entirely from public funds may be more subject to government policy, which sometimes means that exhibitions are expected to reflect the government's views. Moreover, in spite of their popularity,&#xA0; <b>(5)</b>. Consequently, museums that do not charge admission may not always be able to afford ambitious projects, or to buy new items to add to their collections. Lastly, though museum directors want to attract large numbers of visitors,&#xA0; <b>(6)</b>.
  </p>
  <p>
    In conclusion, I believe that children and students should have free admission to museums, while adults should&#xA0; <b>(7)</b>. In this way, museums would be able to raise sufficient money to maintain the quality of their collections and add to them, and, at the same time, fulfil a valuable role in educating the general public.
  </p>
</section>

<section id="body">
<img class="leftFloat" src="../media/set5.2_03.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>
  <ol id="splitquestionList">
    <li id="q1">Choose the best clause or phrase:
      <list class="answerList">

        <li>
          <a id="a1">are reluctant to introduce entrance fees</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a id="a2">have begun to charge entrance fees</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a id="a3">want to charge entrance fees</a>
        </li>
      </list></li>

<p class="linespace"></p>

    <li id="q2">Choose the best clause or phrase:
      <list class="answerList">
        <li>
          <a id="a4">charging no fee would mean the same</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a id="a5">free admission makes it accessible to everyone, regardless of income</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a id="a6">but not everyone can afford it</a>
        </li>
      </list>

    </li>
<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="q3">Choose the best clause or phrase:
      <list class="answerList">
        <li>
          <a id="a7">the number of people who visit them on impulse is also high</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a id="a8">some people visit the same museum two or three times</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a id="a9">some visitors are tourists and school children</a>
        </li>
      </list>

    </li>
<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="q4">Choose the best clause or phrase:
      <list class="answerList">
        <li>
          <a id="a10">they also need to put on exhibitions which make money</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a id="a11">free museums do not suffer from the same constraints, which may mean they present their exhibitions in a more serious way</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a id="a12">free museums need to appeal to a wider public, which means they only put on popular exhibitions</a>
        </li>
      </list>

    </li>
<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="q5">Choose the best clause or phrase:
      <list class="answerList">
        <li>
          <a id="a13">many museums have millions of visitors every year</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a id="a14">hospitals and schools receive priority when it comes to government funding</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a id="a15">museums have to compete for funding with the health service and the education system, both of which tend to receive higher priority</a>
        </li>
      </list>
    </li>
<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="q6">Choose the best clause or phrase:
      <list class="answerList">
        <li>
          <a id="a16">free museums often become unpleasantly overcrowded, especially during holiday periods, which can discourage more serious visitors</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a id="a17">museums are always looking for ways to make their exhibits appeal to a larger audience</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a id="a18">free admission would encourage more visitors to come</a>
        </li>
      </list>

    </li>
<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="q7">Choose the best clause or phrase:
      <list class="answerList">
        <li>
          <a id="a19">not have to pay for them</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a id="a20">be given free entrance</a>
        </li>
        <li>
          <a id="a21">pay a moderate entrance fee</a>
        </li>
      </list>
</li>
<p class="linespace"></p>
<p class="linespace"></p>
  </ol>
</section>

<section id="fb1">
  <p class="feedbacktext">1. The word 'despite' suggests that even though there are pressures to change, many museums are not doing so.</p>
</section>

<section id="fb2">
  <p class="feedbacktext">
    2. a: 'whereas' is used to show contrast, not similarity.
  </p>
  <p class="feedbacktext">
    c: 'Whereas' and 'but' can't be used in the same sentence.
  </p>
</section>

<section id="fb3">
  <p class="feedbacktext">3. This could not be a very useful or meaningful comparison.</p>
</section>

<section id="fb4">
  <p class="feedbacktext">
    4. a: This is a repetition of the statement which begins the sentence. The second half of this sentence should contrast with the first.
  </p>
  <p class="feedbacktext">
    c: The writer is making quite the opposite point.
  </p>
</section>

<section id="fb5">
  <p class="feedbacktext">
    5. a: We use 'in spite of' to show that two facts seem to contradict one another. These two facts together would not be contradictory.
  </p>
  <p class="feedbacktext">
    b: Written like this, it seems that hospitals and schools are 'popular'. This isn't what the writer means to say.
  </p>
</section>

<section id="fb6">
  <p class="feedbacktext">
    6. b: This repeats the statement which begins the sentence.
  </p>
  <p class="feedbacktext">
    c: Notice that the writer uses the word 'though' at the beginning of this sentence. To finish with this phrase would not make any sense.
  </p>
</section>

<section id="fb7">
  <p class="feedbacktext">
    7. a, b: There should be an idea here which contrasts with the first, not which says the same.
  </p>
</section>

<section id="examtips">

<p class="popuptext">It is important in IELTS Writing Task 2 to demonstrate your ability to use complex sentence structures. Using linking words and phrases to join your ideas together is one way to make your language more complex. In Unit 3 we looked at a range of linking expressions and the various purposes they can be used for. This exercise focuses on the use of linking words and phrases to express contrast and concession, such as 'although', 'whereas', 'despite', 'in spite of' and 'however'. Notice how these words and phrases are used in the composition.</p>
</section>

</body>
</bento>