<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="gapfill" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-11-14" />
	<meta name="customised" content="true" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen.css" type="text/css" media="screen" />

	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	
	
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<popups>
    	<popup click="clickme" source="writingtask1" width="500" height="500" />
</popups>

<settings>
 	<param name="delayedMarking" value="true" />
</settings>
  <questions>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q1" block="b1">
      <answer value="F" correct="true" />
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q2" block="b2">
      <answer value="A" correct="true" />
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q3" block="b3">
      <answer value="H" correct="true">
        <feedback source="fb3"/>
      </answer>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
<div id="instruction">		
		Read the arguments on the right and the counter-arguments on the left. Match a counter-argument to each argument by writing the appropriate letter in each gap. Check your answer by reading the completed composition.
</div>
</header>
	
<section id="readingText">

 <div id="reading">
 <p class="hangingIndent"><b>A.</b>&#xA0;Children may be traumatised by disturbing images.</p>

 <p class="hangingIndent"><b>B.</b>&#xA0;Important news events must not be 'censored' for the public, even if the images are unpleasant.</p>

 <p class="hangingIndent"><b>C.</b>&#xA0;Pictures have more impact than words.</p>

 <p class="hangingIndent"><b>D.</b>&#xA0;Some political systems work better when people know exactly what is happening in the world.</p>

 <p class="hangingIndent"><b>E.</b>&#xA0;Television news reports often trivialise tragic events by turning them into entertainment.</p>

 <p class="hangingIndent"><b>F.</b>&#xA0;Too much exposure to disturbing images may accustom us to them, so we no longer react.</p>

 <p class="hangingIndent"><b>G.</b>&#xA0;Victims of violence may not want to be shown on television.</p>

 <p class="hangingIndent"><b>H.</b>&#xA0;Viewers are not always given enough warning before disturbing images are shown.</p>

 <p class="hangingIndent"><b>I.</b>&#xA0;Viewers want to be entertained, not distressed, when they watch television.</p>

</div>
</section>

<section id="body">
<div id="splitquestionList">
	<p><b>Paragraph 1 – Introduction</b></p>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
	
	<p><b>Paragraph 2 – Argument 1 + Counter-argument</b><br/>
	If unpleasant images are shown on television, people may take action.
	</p>
	<p><input id="q1"/></p>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
	
	<p><b>Paragraph 3 – Argument 2 + Counter-argument</b><br/>
	Young people should not be sheltered from the unpleasant realities of the world.
	</p>
	<p><input id="q2"/></p>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
	
	<p><b>Paragraph 4 – Argument 3 + Counter-argument</b><br/>
	If you find the images upsetting, you can turn the television off.
	</p>
	<p><input id="q3"/></p>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
	
	<p><b>Paragraph 5 – Conclusion</b></p>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
	<a id="clickme"><img class="imagetask" src="../media/btn_sampleanswer.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/></a><br/>
</div>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
	<img class="leftFloat" src="../media/set6.2_04.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>
	<p class="linespace"></p>

  
</section>

<section id="fb3">
  <p class="feedbacktext">3. This paragraph is all about the how such images affect children.</p>
</section>

<section id="writingtask1">
	<p class="popuptext">Nowadays, whenever a catastrophic event such as a war or an earthquake takes place, there is usually a television or video camera on hand which will film and broadcast images of it around the world almost instantly, no matter how disturbing they might be. It is often suggested that these are not the kind of pictures we should have to see in our homes. but there are some who think there are very good reasons why such images should be included in television news reports.</p>
	
	<p class="popuptext">Firstly, it is sometimes claimed that when disturbing images of war or some other disastrous event are broadcast, people become motivated to do something to remedy the situation or to help the victims. Unless the public see these images, it is argued, they are unlikely to act. On the other hand, it is also said that if people see too many disturbing or violent scenes on the news, they grow accustomed to them and no longer react as if these events were something unusual. As a result, they may begin to think that what they are seeing is normal or even acceptable.</p>
	
	<p class="popuptext">Secondly, there is the issue of whether or not children should be exposed to such images. It is sometimes argued that television news reports should show the world as it really is and that it is best for children to be aware of this reality. The counter-argument to this, however, is that violent images on television can be particularly disturbing for children, and that some of them may be severely traumatised by seeing such things.</p>
	
	<p class="popuptext">Finally, it is often pointed out that if viewers find images upsetting, they can simply switch off the television or change channel. However, viewers are not always forewarned that a report may include distressing pictures. Besides this, most people would find flicking from one channel to another during a news programme rather frustrating.</p>
</section>

</body>
</bento>