<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="targetspotting" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-11-14" />
	<meta name="customised" content="false" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/presentation.css" type="text/css" media="screen" />

	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	#practiceA {
	text-align: left;
	padding-left: -3px;
	line-height: 22em;
	padding-right: 430%;
	}
	
	#practiceA p {
	padding-left: 17px;
	padding-bottom: 20em;
	}
	</style>
	
	
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<popups>
    	<popup click="clickme" source="sampleanswer" width="500" height="325" />
</popups>
<settings>
 	<param name="delayedMarking" value="true" />
</settings>
  <questions/>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	<div id="instruction">
		
		Read the Writing Task below. You should spend about 20 minutes on this task. You should write at least 150 words. When you have finished, click to see the sample answer.
	</div>
</header>
	
<section id="body">
<div><a id="clickme"><img class="imagetask" src="../media/btn_sampleanswer.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/></a>
  <br/><br/></div>
  <div>
  <img class="rightFloat" src="../media/MM_AW_002.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/></div>
  <div id="practiceA">
  
  <h1>Writing Task</h1>
  <p>The chart shows trends in newspaper circulation in the USA over a forty-year period.</p>
  
  <p>Write a report for a university lecturer describing the information shown in the chart.</p>
 
  <p class="linespace"></p>
 </div>
</section>

<section id="sampleanswer">
<p class="popuptext">The chart shows changes in circulation figures for morning, evening and Sunday newspapers in the United States between 1960 and 1999. Over these four decades there was a marked growth in circulation figures for both Sunday and daily morning papers. Circulation for evening papers, on the other hand, declined steadily.</p>
  
  <p class="popuptext">Throughout the period, Sunday papers maintained a higher circulation than either kind of daily paper. In 1960, for example, the number of copies of Sunday papers sold was almost twice as high as daily sales of morning papers and about a third higher than those of evening papers. Sunday paper circulation continued to grow steadily until it reached a peak of around 62 million copies in 1990. Nine years later, however, this figure had fallen by almost 3 million.</p>
  
  <p class="popuptext">The chart also shows clear trends for both morning and evening newspaper circulation, with the former rising and the latter falling steadily over the four decades. At the beginning of the period, evening papers had a daily circulation of about 35 million copies. There was a small rise of just over a million copies in 1970, but by 1990 the figure had plunged to approximately 20 million. This was followed by a fall of another 10 million in 1999. In contrast, there was a steady growth in the circulation of morning papers, from 24 million in 1960 to 46 million four decades later.</p>
  
  <p class="popuptext">Perhaps changes in reading habits or the use of leisure time among Americans account for these changes.</p>
</section>
</body>
</bento>