<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="targetspotting" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-11-14" />
	<meta name="customised" content="false" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/targetspotting.css" type="text/css" media="screen" />
<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/targetspotting-print.css" type="text/css" media="print" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	
	
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<settings>
 	<param name="delayedMarking" value="false" />
</settings>
  <questions>
    <TargetSpottingQuestion block="b1">
      <answer source="t1" correct="true"/>
    </TargetSpottingQuestion>
    <TargetSpottingQuestion block="b2">
      <answer source="t2" correct="false">
        <feedback source="fb2"/>
      </answer>
    </TargetSpottingQuestion>
    <TargetSpottingQuestion block="b3">
      <answer source="t3" correct="false">
        <feedback source="fb3"/>
      </answer>
    </TargetSpottingQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
<div id="instruction">
	Read the writing tasks and choose the best introductory paragraph. Click A, B or C.
</div>
</header>
	
<section id="body">
	<img class="rightFloat" src="../media/set9.2_07.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"  />
	
	<div id="targetspotting">
	<p><b>More and more people throughout the world are now living to a very old age and it is unreasonable to expect their families to look after them. The state should take responsibility for caring for old people when they are no longer capable of looking after themselves.</b></p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent1"><b><a id="t1">a.&#xA0;&#xA0;Over the course of the last hundred years, life expectancy has increased considerably in most countries of the world. However, problems such as failing health and dementia mean that this growing population of senior citizens needs looking after. The pressures of modern life make it difficult for families to take care of older relatives as they used to in the past so the state should now take on this responsibility.</a></b></p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent1"><b><a id="t2">b.&#xA0;&#xA0;Life expectancy throughout the world has increased dramatically even in the last fifty years. In countries as different as Turkey and Korea, for example, life expectancy has increased by 20 years since 1960. There are three basic reasons why this has occurred.</a></b></p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent1"><b><a id="t3">c.&#xA0;&#xA0;People around the world are living longer than ever before, but is this necessarily a good thing? No doubt most younger and middle-aged people welcome the idea that they will live longer than previous generations did. Yet few of us consider the problems, both for society and for individuals, associated with living to a very old age.</a></b></p>
	
</div>
</section>

<section id="fb2">
  <p class="feedbacktext">It seems from this introduction that the rest of the composition will be about the reasons why people are living longer these days. This is quite irrelevant to the task.</p>
</section>

<section id="fb3">
  <p class="feedbacktext">This candidate is clearly going to write a descriptive composition listing the drawbacks of growing to a very old age. However, the task asks who should look after the older members of society and invites candidates to express their opinions on this issue.</p>
</section>

</body>
</bento>