<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="gapfill" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-11-14" />
	<meta name="customised" content="false" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen.css" type="text/css" media="screen" />
<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen-print.css" type="text/css" media="print" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<popups>
    	<popup click="clickme" source="examtips" width="500" />
	</popups>
<settings>
 	<param name="delayedMarking" value="true" />
</settings>
  <questions>
     <DragQuestion source="q1" block="b1">
      <answer source="a10" correct="true"/>
    </DragQuestion>
    <DragQuestion source="q2" block="b2">
      <answer source="a7" correct="true"/>
    </DragQuestion>
    <DragQuestion source="q3" block="b3">
      <answer source="a5" correct="true"/>
    </DragQuestion>
    <DragQuestion source="q4" block="b4">
      <answer source="a4" correct="true"/>
    </DragQuestion>
    <DragQuestion source="q5" block="b5">
      <answer source="a2" correct="true"/>
	  </DragQuestion>
	    <DragQuestion source="q6" block="b6">
      <answer source="a8" correct="true"/>
	  </DragQuestion>
	    <DragQuestion source="q7" block="b7">
      <answer source="a1" correct="true"/>
	  </DragQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
<div id="instruction">
	The reading passage on the left has seven paragraphs A-G. Choose the best headings for paragraphs A-G from the list of headings on the right. Write the appropriate numbers (1-10) in the gaps. There are more headings than paragraphs, so you will not use them all.
	</div>
</header>



<section id="readingText">
<a id="clickme"><img class="imagetask" src="../media/btn_examtips.jpg" mode="1" id="1002"/></a>
	<br/>
<h8><p>Things that Go Bump in Your Flight</p></h8>
	
	<h2><p>New sensing technologies could improve air safety by providing advance warning of turbulence</p></h2>
	
<div id="reading">
	
	<p class="hangingIndent"><b>A</b>&#xA0;Along with dodgy food, cramped seating and screaming infants, turbulence is one of the banes of modern air travel. Avoiding turbulence is a somewhat haphazard business. Pilots do their best to fly around storms and to steer clear of turbulent areas reported by aircraft further along the route. But a series of experiments that has just finished in Colorado could eliminate some of the guesswork, by enabling airliners' existing radar systems to pick up signs of the most common kind of turbulence, called "convective" turbulence, with just a simple software upgrade.</p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent"><b>B</b>&#xA0;The radar systems in question are currently used to detect an even more undesirable atmospheric condition called wind-shear. This dangerous phenomenon occurs during a storm, when a rapidly descending column of air hits the ground and spreads out. An aircraft flying into such a column experiences a headwind, followed by a downdraft and then a tailwind. If the aircraft is flying at a low altitude, the sudden tailwind can rob it of lift and cause a crash.</p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent"><b>C</b>&#xA0;Wind-shear is detected by transmitting a stream of radio pulses in front of the aircraft. By analysing a tiny change in frequency, called the Doppler shift, caused when the pulses bounce off moving raindrops, it is possible to work out how fast the drops are moving and hence the pattern of air movement in front of the aircraft. An alarm sounds if the characteristic sign of wind-shear, which is a headwind with a tailwind behind it, is detected. After several crashes in the 1970s and 1980s, such radar systems are now installed on many modern airliners.</p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent"><b>D</b>&#xA0;These systems are, however, used only at altitudes below 700m (2,300ft) and are switched off during the rest of the flight. This set Larry Cornman, an atmospheric scientist at the National Centre for Atmospheric Research (NCAR) in Boulder, Colorado, thinking. Could not the same equipment be put to use during flight to detect turbulence?</p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent"><b>E</b>&#xA0;In theory, the answer is yes. Raindrops in calm air are all carried along at the same speed and in the same direction, so radio pulses bouncing off them are all Doppler-shifted by the same amount. Raindrops within a turbulent region, in contrast, have a wide range of speeds and directions as they are tossed around, resulting in a wide range of Doppler shifts. So by correctly processing the readings from the radar system, it ought to be possible to detect approaching pockets of turbulence.</p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent"><b>F</b>&#xA0;Only about 60% of turbulence, however, is associated with storms. Radar systems cannot, for example, detect "clear-air turbulence" (CAT), a particularly nasty variety that, as its name suggests, occurs unexpectedly in clear air. Even with no raindrops around to bounce radar pulses off, CAT can still be detected using a light-based radar or "lidar", which measures how light from a laser beam is scattered by tiny airborne particles called aerosols. A lidar-based CAT detector was tested successfully last year by America's space agency, NASA, and further tests are planned.</p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent"><b>G</b>&#xA0;Yet another kind of turbulence is terrain-induced, and causes problems at airports in mountainous regions. But it too can be predicted. Using readings from an instrument-equipped plane in the air, in combination with ground-based windspeed sensors and radars, it is possible to build a mathematical model for a particular airport that can then be used to predict turbulence solely from measurements taken on the ground. Such a system is already in place at Hong Kong airport, and NCAR researchers are now testing a more advanced system at Juneau, Alaska, an airport where terrain-induced turbulence is a particular problem.</p>
	
	<p>The Economist</p>
	
	</div>
</section>

		<section id="noscroll">
  <span id="a1" draggable="true">Making predictions from the ground</span>
  <span id="a2" draggable="true">How convective turbulence could be identified</span>
  <span id="a3" draggable="true">Building model airports</span>
  <span id="a4" draggable="true">A new application for an old system</span>
  <span id="a5" draggable="true">How wind-shear is identified</span>
  <span id="a6" draggable="true">Dangerous headwinds</span>
  <span id="a7" draggable="true">A potentially deadly phenomenon</span>
  <span id="a8" draggable="true">Another method for fine weather</span>
    <span id="a9" draggable="true">Detecting rain</span>
  <span id="a10" draggable="true">Current methods and new research</span>
</section>

<section id="body">
<img class="leftFloat" src="../media/set3_01.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>
  <ol id="splitquestionList">
 <li id="1">Paragraph A<tab/>&#xA0;<input id="q1" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="2">Paragraph B<tab/>&#xA0;<input id="q2" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="3">Paragraph C<tab/>&#xA0;<input id="q3" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="4">Paragraph D<tab/>&#xA0;<input id="q4" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="5">Paragraph E<tab/>&#xA0;<input id="q5" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="6">Paragraph F<tab/>&#xA0;<input id="q6" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="7">Paragraph G<tab/>&#xA0;<input id="q7" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
	</ol>
</section>

<section id="examtips">
<p class="popuptext1"><b>Questions 1-7 - Matching headings to paragraphs</b></p>
<p class="popuptext2">First look through the list of headings. Then skim quickly through the whole passage to get a general idea of the content and how it's organized. Next you should skim through the first paragraph more carefully without worrying too much about any unknown words. Your aim is to understand the gist, or main idea, of each paragraph. Then find the heading that expresses the same idea. Don't expect to find exactly the same vocabulary in the headings, but look for words that mean the same. Do the same with all the other paragraphs. In some cases you should be able to make a match by finding the topic sentence. This is often the first or last sentence in a paragraph, but it may be somewhere in the middle, which is why it's a good idea to skim through the whole paragraph.</p>

<p class="popuptext">If you can't find a heading for a paragraph, don't spend a long time trying to match it. Leave it and go back to it at the end when you'll have fewer headings to choose from.</p>

<p class="popuptext">Notice there are three extra headings that don't match any the paragraphs.</p>
</section>
</body>
</bento>