<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="gapfill" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-12-09" />
	<meta name="customised" content="true" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen.css" type="text/css" media="screen" />
<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen-print.css" type="text/css" media="print" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
  <settings>
    <param name="delayedMarking" value="true"/>
  </settings>
  <questions>
     <DragQuestion source="q1" block="b1">
      <answer source="a9" correct="true"/>
    </DragQuestion>
    <DragQuestion source="q2" block="b2">
      <answer source="a4" correct="true"/>
    </DragQuestion>
    <DragQuestion source="q3" block="b3">
      <answer source="a10" correct="true"/>
    </DragQuestion>
    <DragQuestion source="q4" block="b4">
      <answer source="a2" correct="true"/>
    </DragQuestion>
    <DragQuestion source="q5" block="b5">
      <answer source="a7" correct="true"/>
	  </DragQuestion>
	    <DragQuestion source="q6" block="b6">
      <answer source="a5" correct="true"/>
	  </DragQuestion>
	    <DragQuestion source="q7" block="b7">
      <answer source="a11" correct="true"/>
	  </DragQuestion>
	    <DragQuestion source="q8" block="b8">
      <answer source="a6" correct="true"/>
    </DragQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
<div id="instruction">
	The reading passage on the left has eight paragraphs A-H. Choose the most suitable headings for paragraphs A-H from the list of headings on the right. Write the appropriate numbers (i-xi) in gaps 1-8. There are more headings than paragraphs, so you will not use all of them.
	</div>
</header>



<section id="readingText">
	
	<h1>Tomorrow the world</h1>
	<p>Backpacking is easy, it's cheap, and it's the most fun you'll ever have in your life. If you've got the chance, take it. Going is easy – the rest of this article will tell you how.</p>
	<div id="reading">
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>A</b>&#xA0;Settle on a budget before you go. Add up your air fares, insurance and estimated living expenses, then add a 50% peace-of-mind supplement: there's nothing worse than fretfully counting the ringgit when you should be watching the sunset. If you're leaving savings in the UK, it's worth asking a reliable friend or relative to handle your finances. Ask your bank for a third-party mandate, which allows a nominated person to act on your accounts: this means you can leave your nest egg earning interest in a savings account, and they can transfer funds to your current account as you need them. Choose carefully, though: you'll have to trust them to the end of the earth – literally.</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>B</b>&#xA0;You do need good medical cover. In the EU, most healthcare is free or subsidised but beyond that you're on your own – and being airlifted out of Borneo for treatment in Jakarta will not be cheap. Other cover might not be appropriate: there's really no point insuring luggage if your backpack and its contents are worth only £50.</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>C</b>&#xA0;There are risks involved in all travel, but a few sensible precautions will help you limit them. Stick to the beaten track at first. It may be tempting to play the intrepid traveller and jump on the local bus to God-knows-where in your first week, but your lack of nous will mark you out as "just off the boat". Get used to the locals before you play at being Dr Livingstone. Scams and rip-offs, too numerous and inventive to list, proliferate. Use your common sense. If a deal seems too good to be true, walk away.</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>D</b>&#xA0;You're in someone else's home, and the onus is on you to find out the etiquette and observe it. The locals know you're foreign, and will usually make allowances, but correct behaviour will impress and make striking up a friendship much easier.</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>E</b>&#xA0;There are now internet cafes in the most far-flung parts of the world: use them by opening an account. They're simple, free and allow you to send and receive from any internet-enabled computer on the planet. Otherwise, there's post – sometimes unreliable, but a letter somehow means more than an email – or phone calls.</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>F</b>&#xA0;It's amazing how fast you adapt to the local economy: I've caught myself turning down a decent hotel room because it was more expensive than the grotty one next door. Retain your sense of perspective: a pound here and there is worth it to smooth your way. If roughing it is becoming a grind, a night every so often in a three-star hotel, with fluffy towels and satellite television, can change your mood completely.</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>G</b>&#xA0;In many poorer countries, there is a tourist price (which you don't want to pay) and a local price (which you do). Bargaining is essential, and in most places expected. But remember, however tight your budget, you're probably a lot better off than your hosts: accept that you'll pay a little more than they do, and when you strike a deal, stump up cheerfully. As a backpacker, the money you pay is going straight into the local economy, rather than being creamed off by tour companies, so you could view the premium as your small contribution to world wealth redistribution.</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>H</b>&#xA0;You left the UK in a state of nervousness, excitement and anticipation, entering the unknown: coming back to the cold, grey and familiar can be the hardest part of the whole experience. Before you go, set aside some funds to come back to, and resolve not to touch them while you're away. You'll need a fair sum to set you up again. And remember, the world isn't going anywhere. The wonders and the weirdness will be there next year, and the year after – so get out that atlas and start planning!</p>
	<p>Stephen Bleach, The Sunday Times.</p>
	  </div>
</section>

<section id="noscroll">
  <span id="a1" draggable="true">Researching your route</span>
  <span id="a2" draggable="true">Be sensitive to cultural differences</span>
  <span id="a3" draggable="true">Choosing the right accommodation</span>
  <span id="a4" draggable="true">Taking out insurance</span>
  <span id="a5" draggable="true">Treat yourself occasionally</span>
  <span id="a6" draggable="true">Returning home</span>
  <span id="a7" draggable="true">Staying in touch</span>
  <span id="a8" draggable="true">Keeping an open mind</span>
  <span id="a9" draggable="true">Taking care of your finances</span>
  <span id="a10" draggable="true">Safety first</span>
  <span id="a11" draggable="true">Don't be mean</span>
</section>

<section id="body">
   <img class="leftFloat" src="../media/RD_TTW_001.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>
  <ol id="splitquestionList">
    <li id="1">Paragraph A<tab/><input id="q1" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="2">Paragraph B<tab/><input id="q2" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="3">Paragraph C<tab/><input id="q3" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="4">Paragraph D<tab/><input id="q4" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="5">Paragraph E<tab/><input id="q5" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="6">Paragraph F<tab/><input id="q6" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="7">Paragraph G<tab/><input id="q7" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="8">Paragraph H<tab/><input id="q8" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
  </ol>
</section>

</body>
</bento>