<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="gapfill" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-12-09" />
	<meta name="customised" content="false" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen.css" type="text/css" media="screen" />
<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen-print.css" type="text/css" media="print" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
  <settings>
    <param name="delayedMarking" value="true"/>
  </settings>
  <questions>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q1" block="b1">
      <answer value="C" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q2" block="b2">
      <answer value="E" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q3" block="b3">
      <answer value="A" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q4" block="b4">
      <answer value="F" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q5" block="b5">
      <answer value="B" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q6" block="b6">
      <answer value="H" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q7" block="b7">
      <answer value="D" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="{#q8,#q9}" block="b8">
	  <answer value="C" correct="true" synonymGroup="C"/>
	  <answer value="G" correct="true" synonymGroup="G1"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="{#q10,#q11}" block="b10">
      <answer value="B" correct="true" synonymGroup="B"/>
	  <answer value="E" correct="true" synonymGroup="E1"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="{#q12,#q13}" block="b12">
      <answer value="E" correct="true" synonymGroup="E2"/>
	  <answer value="G" correct="true" synonymGroup="G2"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
<div id="instruction">
	Look at the eight book reviews on the left. Answer the questions on the right by writing the letters of the appropriate books A-H in gaps 1-10. You may use any letter more than once.
	</div>
</header>
	


<section id="readingText">
<img class="photo2" src="../media/RD_WBC_001.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>

<h1><p>Welcome to the BOOKS etc. Catalogue</p></h1>

<p>Within these pages, you will find details of books to give, books to treasure, books to read and re-read for years to come. Whether you are seeking inspiration for gift ideas or looking for a book to indulge your own reading tastes, the titles featured here will provide the answers.</p>

<div id="reading">
<p class="hangingIndent"><h7>A ROSES ARE RED - James Patterson</h7>
<br/>
A fast-moving and tautly-plotted thriller featuring the ever-dependable Alex Cross. Cross is forced to delve into the dangerous mind of a psychopath who has masterminded a succession of increasingly violent robberies. A tense, compelling read.</p>

<p class="hangingIndent"><h7>B VICKY ANGEL - Jacqueline Wilson</h7>
<br/>
8 to 12-year-olds will squeal with delight to find Vicky Angel, Wilson's latest extraordinary creation. Young Jade loses her larger-than-life best friend in a tragic accident but nothing, not even death, can end their amazing friendship. Another classic from this award-winning author.</p>

<p class="hangingIndent"><h7>C LES LIAISONS CULINAIRES - Andreas Staikos</h7>
<br/>
As succulent as a stuffed vine leaf, as delicious as a feta salad, this is a picaresque tale of whimsy in which two men duel for the heart of the same woman using nothing more than culinary expertise and guile. Prepare to have your taste buds tickled and your heart gladdened. Superb.</p>

<p class="hangingIndent"><h7>D LOOK TO WINWARD - Iain M. Banks</h7>
<br/>
If you are a science fiction aficionado, look no further than Iain M. Banks. With an imaginative scope as seemingly boundless as the stellar space in which his stories are set, Banks has the power to transport his readers to universes far beyond our own.</p>

<p class="hangingIndent"><h7>E ON WRITING - Stephen King</h7>
<br/>
Master storyteller Stephen King reflects on the road accident that almost put paid to his writing career and is prompted by this to explore the circumstances that led him to become a writer in the first place. Rich in practical advice for the would-be writer, this is also a rare insight into the working methods of the world's most successful author.</p>

<p class="hangingIndent"><h7>F LONDON: THE BIOGRAPHY - Peter Ackroyd</h7>
<br/>
Peter Akroyd's unconventional approach to the city that has informed so much of his previous work, both fiction and non- fiction, is to treat it as a living organism that has evolved and changed over the centuries. He finds as many connections through time as he does in three-dimensional space and the portrait that emerges is therefore richly complex and totally engaging.</p>

<p class="hangingIndent"><h7>G APPETITE - Nigel Slater</h7>
<br/>
Food to console, food to excite &#x2013; whatever your appetite, Nigel Slater has suggestions to delight the senses and sustain the soul. Slater's infectious enthusiasm will soften the sternest sceptic, while his refreshing impatience for the tyrannical 'straightjacket' of the recipe will empower even the most timid tyro.</p>

<p class="hangingIndent"><h7>H GENOME - Matt Ridley</h7>
<br/>
Subtitled 'the autobiography of a species in 23 chapters' (one for each chromosome), this is an indispensable book for anyone who would seek to understand recent developments at the frontiers of genetics and their implications for the human race. A timely and thought-provoking book.</p>

<p class="hangingIndent">Books etc Christmas Catalogue 2000.</p>
</div>
</section>

<section id="body">
  <ol id="splitquestionList">
    <li id="1">Which book is a love story?<br/>
		<input id="q1"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="2">Which book is autobiographical?<br/>
		<input id="q2"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="3">Which book features criminal acts?<br/>
		<input id="q3"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="4">Which book describes the history and development of a place?<br/>
		<input id="q4"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="5">Which book is aimed at children?<br/>
		<input id="q5"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="6">Which book discusses an area of scientific research?<br/>
		<input id="q6"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="7">Which book is set in space?<br/>
		<input id="q7"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="8">Which TWO books share the theme of cooking?<br/>
		<input id="q8"/><br/>
		<input id="q9"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="9">Which TWO books feature an accident?<br/>
		<input id="q10"/><br/>
		<input id="q11"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="10">Which TWO books would interest readers who want to develop a practical skill?<br/>
		<input id="q12"/><br/>
		<input id="q13"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
  </ol>
</section>

</body>
</bento>