<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="multiplechoice" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-12-09" />
	<meta name="customised" content="true" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen.css" type="text/css" media="screen" />
<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen-print.css" type="text/css" media="print" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
  <settings>
    <param name="delayedMarking" value="true"/>
  </settings>
  <questions>
     <DragQuestion source="q1" block="b1">
      <answer source="a3" correct="true"/>
    </DragQuestion>
    <DragQuestion source="q2" block="b2">
      <answer source="a2" correct="true">
        <feedback source="fb2"/>
      </answer>
    </DragQuestion>
    <DragQuestion source="q3" block="b3">
      <answer source="a1" correct="true"/>
    </DragQuestion>
    <DragQuestion source="q4" block="b4">
      <answer source="a1" correct="true">
        <feedback source="fb4"/>
      </answer>
    </DragQuestion>
    <DragQuestion source="q5" block="b5">
      <answer source="a2" correct="true"/>
	  </DragQuestion>
    <DragQuestion source="q6" block="b6">
      <answer source="a3" correct="true">
        <feedback source="fb6"/>
      </answer>
	  </DragQuestion>
    <DragQuestion source="q7" block="b7">
      <answer source="a2" correct="true"/>
    </DragQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
<div id="instruction">
	Look at the information on the left about the three voluntary organizations. Answer the questions by clicking the letters of the appropriate organizations A-C below questions 1-7. You may use any letter more than once.
	</div>
</header>

<section id="noscroll">
  <span id="a1" draggable="true">Operations Crossroads Africa</span>
  <span id="a2" draggable="true">Global Citizens Network</span>
  <span id="a3" draggable="true">Visions in Action</span>
</section>
	
<section id="body">
<img class="leftFloat" src="../media/RD_IDP_001.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>
  <ol id="splitquestionList">
    
    <li>Which organisation only accepts volunteers who have either academic qualifications or work experience?<br/><input id="q1" type="droptarget"/></li>
     <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li>Which organisation covers transport costs for some volunteers?<br/><input id="q2" type="droptarget"/></li>
     <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li>Which organisation gives volunteers the opportunity to explore the host country?<br/><input id="q3" type="droptarget"/></li>
     <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li>Which organisation provided the framework for the development of another organization?<br/><input id="q4" type="droptarget"/></li>
     <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li>Which organisation has projects lasting less than a month?<br/><input id="q5" type="droptarget"/></li>
     <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li>Which organisation does NOT have projects in rural areas?<br/><input id="q6" type="droptarget"/></li>
     <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li>Which organisation does NOT require volunteers to cover the cost of housing?<br/><input id="q7" type="droptarget"/></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
  </ol>
</section>

<section id="fb2">
  <p class="feedbacktext">2. This applies to volunteers who are team leaders.</p>
</section>

<section id="fb4">
  <p class="feedbacktext">4. The Peace Corps is another organisation similar to those described in the text.</p>
</section>

<section id="fb6">
  <p class="feedbacktext">6. Urban means in the city, rural in the countryside.</p>
</section>

<section id="readingText">
<h1>International development projects</h1>

<h7><p>Operations Crossroads Africa</p></h7>
<p>Founded in 1957, Operations Crossroads Africa sends people to work on community-initiated development projects in Africa and Brazil. Crossroads has projects in 10-12 Africa countries and Brazil each summer. Over 10,000 people have participated in Crossroads since its inception, and it was the model for the Peace Corps.</p>

<p>200 volunteers are recruited annually onto four types of project: agriculture/reforestation; construction/community development; community health/medical; education/training (including women's development). Volunteers work 5-6 hours a day. Projects are six weeks long and are in rural villages. The work groups (8-10 volunteers per group) then travel for one week in the host country. All groups work with local counterparts. The programmes run from mid-June to mid- August.</p>

<p>Volunteers are aged between 17 and 35. knowledge of French is preferred for francophone countries and Portuguese for Brazil and Guinea Bissau. Participants in community health/medical projects must be science, nursing, pre-med majors or in nursing, medical or public health programmes. Applicants of any nationality are welcomed. Participants must attend a 3-day orientation in New York prior to departure, paying their own way to New York, participation fee and all other expenses.</p>
   
<h7>Global Citizens Network</h7>
<p>GCN is a non-profit organization that sends teams of volunteers to rural communities around the world. Projects are determined by the villages that GCN is in partnership with and are aimed at promoting cross-cultural understanding. The projects vary but have included building a health clinic, teaching in a primary school and developing ecotourism.</p>

<p>Volunteers are not required to have special skills but some knowledge of Spanish would be helpful for Guatemala and the Yucatan. The minimum age is 18 unless accompanied by a parent or guardian. Trips last one, two or three weeks only, all year round. Volunteers pay a contribution which ranges from US$550 to US$1,600 depending on the programme.</p>

<p>The cost of transportation to the programme is also at the volunteer's expense. Accommodation is provided. Volunteers are drawn from throughout the world but mainly from the US and Canada.</p>

<p>Returned volunteers who are interested can also apply to be team leaders for other GCN trips. Potential team leaders have to be recommended by their own team leader and attend a training session. Team leaders can be any nationality and, although the position is unpaid, airfares and most in-country expenses will be paid.</p>

<h7>Visions in Action</h7>
<p>Visions in Action is an international non-profit organization founded in 1988 out of the conviction that there is much that individuals can learn from, and contribute to, the developing world by working as part of a community of volunteers committed to achieving social justice in an urban setting. Visions volunteers work side-by-side with host country nationals, allowing a genuine understanding of the country's needs to emerge.</p>

<p>60-80 volunteers per year work in indigenous or expatriate organisations as development journalists, community workers, project managers, low-income housing facilitators and healthcare assistants, etc. Placements are available in the following sectors: agriculture, appropriate technology, children, communication/journalism, education, environment/natural resources, food/nutrition, family planning, health, housing, human rights/law, mental or physical disabilities, natural science, refugees/relief, small business, social science, women and youth in South Africa, Zimbabwe, Uganda, Burkina Faso, Tanzania, and Mexico.</p>
  
<p>All programmes last for one year, with the exception of South Africa and Mexico, which have six-month and one-year options. Applicants may be of any nationality, but they must have a college degree or equivalent work experience. Programmes begin at various times in the year. The average cost of participating in a programme is $5,000. Volunteers must pay for all their costs. The programme fee includes housing, medical insurance and work visas.</p>

<p>Abridged book extracts relating to 'Global Citizens Network' (page 36), 'Operation Crossroads Africa' (pages 44-45), and 'Visions in Action' (pages 213-214) from Directory of International Voluntary Work by Louise Whetter and Victoria Pybus, Seventh Edition, Vacation Work Publications.</p>

</section> 

<section id="rt2001">
  <p align="left">This text gives information to would-be volunteers about projects run by three different voluntary organisations. The text is clearly divided into three sections, one for each organisation. The text is purely factual and all the exercises simply test your ability to find information.</p>
  <p align="left">Question 1Search for words connected with qualifications and experience, for example 'degree', 'graduate', 'qualified', 'skills', 'practice' etc.</p>
  <p align="left">Question 2Search for words to do with travel, such as 'fare', 'tickets', 'expenses', 'flights' etc.</p>
  <p align="left">Question 3The host country is the place where volunteers will work. Search for words to do with explore, such as 'travel', 'find out', 'discover', 'get about', ' sightseeing' etc.</p>
  <p align="left">Question 4In other words, another famous organisation, not mentioned in the text, based itself on one of the three organisations described here. Which one?</p>
  <p align="left">Question 5Search for periods of time less than a month, 'a week' for example.</p>
  <p align="left">Question 6'Rural' means in the countryside. Do you know what the opposite is?</p>
  <p align="left">Question 7Search for other words for 'housing' such as 'accommodation', 'lodgings', 'rooms' etc.</p>

</section>

</body>
</bento>