<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="multiplechoice" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2012-01-16" />
	<meta name="customised" content="false" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen.css" type="text/css" media="screen" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen-print.css" type="text/css" media="print" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
  <settings>
    <param name="delayedMarking" value="true"/>
  </settings>
  <questions>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q1">
      <answer source="a1" correct="true"/>
      <answer source="a2" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a3" correct="false"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q2">
      <answer source="a4" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a5" correct="true"/>
      <answer source="a6" correct="false"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q3">
      <answer source="a7" correct="true"/>
      <answer source="a8" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a9" correct="false"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q4">
      <answer source="a10" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a11" correct="true"/>
      <answer source="a12" correct="false"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q5">
      <answer source="a13" correct="true"/>
      <answer source="a14" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a15" correct="false"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
<div id="instruction">
		Questions 8-12. Read the passage on the left and look at the statements on the right (Questions 8-12). Click on the best option; true, false or not given. TRUE if the statement is true; FALSE if the statement is false ; NOT GIVEN if the information is not given in the passage.
</div>
</header>
	

<section id="readingText">
	<img class="photo2" src="../media/gt_set9_02.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>
	<h1><p>Practical Guide to Crime Prevention Watch Scheme</p></h1>
	
	<div id="reading">
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>A</b>&#xA0;It is the job of the police to fight crime, but we can all help to bring crime down. Most crime is against property, not people, and not many crimes are carefully planned. Most are committed by young men on the spur of the moment when they see the chance &#x2014; possessions left in a car or a door or window to a house left open. But you can reduce the risk by securing your car and home. This will also help the police, by giving them more time to tackle serious crime. And that's good for you and your family &#x2014; because it makes your neighbourhood a safer place to live in.</p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>B</b>&#xA0;Watch schemes are a way for people in an area to get together to help stop crime and make their neighbourhood a safer place. They are known by several different names in different areas where they work &#x2014; Neighbourhood Watch, Home Watch, Community Watch &#x2014; but they all work along similar lines, have similar aims and are built on the same idea of looking after one another and the neighbourhood.</p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>C</b>&#xA0;Schemes usually start when the police or local people see a crime problem, such as a lot of burglaries, which they want to reduce. Neighbourhood Watch schemes can make an area safer and can make people feel more secure because they know something is being done about crime.</p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>D</b>&#xA0;Groups can vary in size, depending on the area and what people want. They target concerns &#x2014; like burglary, vandalism or graffiti and devise ways of dealing with them. Individual members decide how active they want to be in the scheme. You could become a committee member or even co-ordinator of a group &#x2014; or your part could be just keeping an eye on your neighbour's house while they're away. Schemes develop close links with the police, who can provide advice and information about the local problems. People are advised how to make their homes more secure and they can mark their property, using post-coding equipment, which is often owned by the scheme. Well-run schemes can have big impact on local crime.</p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>E</b>&#xA0;Talk to neighbours and tell the police you want to set up a scheme. Someone with time to meet the police and neighbours must be chosen to be the scheme co-ordinator.</p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>F</b>&#xA0;Although the police will do all they can, it is up to the members to keep a scheme going. Many schemes use newsletters to pass on advice or information. Meetings and social events help to bring Neighbourhood Watch  members together.</p>
	
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>G</b>&#xA0;Watches need not to be confined to residential neighbourhoods. For instance, Business Watch can be very effective in high streets and industrial estates. Farm Watches can encourage farmers to keep an eye on one another's livestock and machinery. Boat Watches can greatly improve the security of marinas and harbours.</p>

	</div>
	
	<h7><p>Glossary</p></h7>
  <ol id="splitreadingList">
	<li>post-coding equipment: a tool used to mark valuable items with owner's postcode. The marking makes it harder for a thief to sell property to a dealer, and easier for the police to return the property if it is found.</li>
</ol>
	
	<p>Practical Ways to Crack Crime &#x2014; The Family Guide &#x2014; 2nd edition The Home Office.</p>

</section>

<section id="body">
  <ol id="splitquestionList">

    <p class="hangingIndent2">8.<tab/>All Watch schemes generally have the same objectives.</p>
	<list class="answerList1">
	<li><a id="a1">True</a></li><li><a id="a2">False</a></li><li><a id="a3">Not given</a></li></list>
    <p class="linespace"></p>

    <p class="hangingIndent2">9.<tab/>Watch schemes are based in residential areas.</p>
	<list class="answerList1">
	<li><a id="a4">True</a></li><li><a id="a5">False</a></li><li><a id="a6">Not given</a></li></list>
    <p class="linespace"></p>

    <p class="hangingIndent2">10.<tab/>Watch scheme groups vary in size.</p>
	<list class="answerList1"><li><a id="a7">True</a></li><li><a id="a8">False</a></li><li><a id="a9">Not given</a></li>
	</list>
    <p class="linespace"></p>

    <p class="hangingIndent2">11.<tab/>All Watch scheme members have access to post-coding equipment.</p>
	<list class="answerList1"><li><a id="a10">True</a></li><li><a id="a11">False</a></li><li><a id="a12">Not given</a></li>
	</list>
    <p class="linespace"></p>

    <p class="hangingIndent2">12.<tab/>Each Watch scheme is managed by a co-ordinator.</p>
	<list class="answerList1"><li><a id="a13">True</a></li><li><a id="a14">False</a></li><li><a id="a15">Not given</a></li>
	</list>
    <p class="linespace"></p>
  </ol>
</section>

</body>
</bento>