<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="multiplechoice" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2012-01-16" />
	<meta name="customised" content="false" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen.css" type="text/css" media="screen" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen-print.css" type="text/css" media="print" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
  <settings>
    <param name="delayedMarking" value="true"/>
  </settings>
  <questions>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q1">
      <answer source="a1" correct="true"/>
      <answer source="a2" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a3" correct="false"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q2">
      <answer source="a4" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a5" correct="true"/>
      <answer source="a6" correct="false"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q3">
      <answer source="a7" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a8" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a9" correct="true"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q4">
      <answer source="a10" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a11" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a12" correct="true"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q5">
      <answer source="a13" correct="true"/>
      <answer source="a14" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a15" correct="false"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
<div id="instruction">		
		Questions 11-15. Do the statements on the right agree with the views of the writer? YES - the statement agrees with the views of the writer; NO - the statement contradicts the views of the writer; NOT GIVEN - it is impossible to say what the writer thinks about this.
</div>
</header>
	
<section id="readingText">

	<h1>FOR AN ECOLOGY OF LEARNING</h1>
	
	<p><b>Despite decades of effort the world still counts almost one billion illiterate adults. Why?</b></p>

	<div id="reading">
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>A</b>&#xA0;Results in adult literacy training fall far short of investments made. But above all, they fall short of efforts devoted to the endeavour both by the learners themselves and their communities. World Bank studies even conclude that they have never produced results anywhere, thus enabling planners to justify investing exclusively in primary schooling. Consequently, since the mid 1970s, spending on adult literacy has seriously diminished. At best, that is in India, it represents 6% to 8% of the education budget. Elsewhere, it rarely goes above 1% or 2%.</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>B</b>&#xA0;Beyond financial questions, this failure is above all one of approach. For a long time, it was considered that illiterates suffered from an illness which could be eradicated like smallpox. There were arguments over method &#x2013; everybody was looking for a miracle cure. But in the field of education, there are no universal vaccinations. Believing to have found one in the European model &#x2013; one language, one country, one territory &#x2013; many developing countries strapped themselves into a monolinguistic yoke.</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>C</b>&#xA0;We now know that literacy training must not only be conducted in maternal languages but that learning materials must also be produced in the logic of these languages. It's enough to learn to read and write in one of them in order to transfer these skills to another. Multilingualism is a scarecrow. In reality, a natural internal regulation takes place: a person moves from one language to another according to need, notably when he or she attempts to communicate with the outside world. In Nigeria, rich in 410 languages, 45% of the population speaks three.</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>D</b>&#xA0;More generally, experience proves that learning must consider the individual socio-economic and cultural context. Certain societies did without a written language for centuries. We are more and more conscious of the fact that societies with an oral tradition have developed mnemotechnical methods enabling them to conserve, organize and re-use information. These capacities are so strong that elementary literacy techniques are insufficient to impose other mental processes, or change the way people organize their lives. In everyday life, modes of communication remain the same and people risk reverting to illiteracy.</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>E</b>&#xA0;To avoid this, we must above all create an environment which calls for written communication. We must create an ecology of learning. This is the main aim of post-literacy activities. These enable the learner to consolidate acquired skills, to move ahead and apply new knowledge. People involve themselves more deeply when they realize they can no longer function without writing.</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>F</b>&#xA0;But the most difficult task is to create a stimulating environment which encourages new literates to move to the next stage, where they have the possibility and an acquired taste for reading, and the desire to create their own reading materials. To achieve this, we usually adopt a pragmatic approach by publishing small booklets on practical themes. A study in Tanzania revealed the great popularity among new literates of manuals on health, savings, agriculture, grazing, etc. In Senegal, where technical manuals failed to capture the interest of new readers, an NGO got the idea of transcribing the epopee of the Peuls into small books. They sold so well that the NGO was forced to do several re-editions.</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>G</b>&#xA0;The visual environment is equally effective. Advertising, for example, now written exclusively in the dominant language, should be flooding the market in the local languages used for literacy training. The same goes for official documents &#x2013; deeds, birth certificates, ID cards, etc. In my country, Mali, these are most often written in French whereas they should be available in two or three languages. Why should people become literate in their own languages if these are not recognized?</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>H</b>&#xA0;We have learned a great deal from past failures and today there is reason for hope. Decision makers are increasingly convinced of the key role played by literacy. The World Bank is realizing that it's not enough to teach children to read and write: the best results have been obtained in the framework of intergenerational learning &#x2013; in which parents are involved. Moreover, in many countries, very few youngsters have access to secondary school and fall back into illiteracy. A large proportion of adolescents and young adults need non-formal basic education.</p>
	<p class="hangingIndent">
	<b>I</b>&#xA0;We are also abandoning the idea that the illiterate lives in total ignorance and only in developing countries. We've noticed that in the most remote villages, there are people who possess very sophisticated knowledge and succeed in transmitting this wisdom without the need for writing either words or concepts borrowed from foreign languages. We recognize &#x2013; finally &#x2013; that we must build on what people are doing themselves; in fact people must do their own building.</p>
	</div>
	<p><b>Glossary</b>&#xA0;NGO: non-governmental organisation. A non-profit independent organisation that works at an international level to improve social, health or environmental conditions.</p>
	
	<p>epopee: epic poems.Peuls: a primarily Muslim people found in many parts of West Africa.</p>
	
	<p>Adama Ouane, Section for Literacy and Adult Education, UNESCO, UNESCO Sources, June 1997, Section: FOCUS: Dossier, p. 10.</p>
	
</section>

<section id="body">
  <img class="leftFloat" src="../media/EN_GR_002.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>
  <ol id="splitquestionList">
  
    <li id="q1">Insufficient progress has been made in improving literacy levels worldwide.<list class="answerList"><li><a id="a1">Yes</a></li><li><a id="a2">No</a></li><li><a id="a3">Not given</a></li></list></li>
    <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="q2">More use should be made of the European approach to illiteracy.<list class="answerList"><li><a id="a4">Yes</a></li><li><a id="a5">No</a></li><li><a id="a6">Not given</a></li></list></li>
    <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="q3">Literacy training techniques should be based on research findings.<list class="answerList"><li><a id="a7">Yes</a></li><li><a id="a8">No</a></li><li><a id="a9">Not given</a></li></list></li>
    <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="q4">Learners who make use of the visual environment make more rapid progress.<list class="answerList"><li><a id="a10">Yes</a></li><li><a id="a11">No</a></li><li><a id="a12">Not given</a></li></list></li>
    <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="q5">People need to take responsibility for their own learning.<list class="answerList"><li><a id="a13">Yes</a></li><li><a id="a14">No</a></li><li><a id="a15">Not given</a></li></list></li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
  </ol>
</section>

</body>
</bento>