<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="multiplechoice" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-12-09" />
	<meta name="customised" content="true" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen.css" type="text/css" media="screen" />
<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen-print.css" type="text/css" media="print" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	 
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
  <settings>
    <param name="delayedMarking" value="true"/>
  </settings>
  <questions>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q1">
      <answer source="a1" correct="true"/>
      <answer source="a2" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a3" correct="false"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q2">
      <answer source="a4" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a5" correct="true"/>
      <answer source="a6" correct="false"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q3">
      <answer source="a7" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a8" correct="true"/>
      <answer source="a9" correct="false"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q4">
      <answer source="a10" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a11" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a12" correct="true"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q5">
      <answer source="a13" correct="true"/>
      <answer source="a14" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a15" correct="false"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
    <MultipleChoiceQuestion block="q6">
      <answer source="a16" correct="false"/>
      <answer source="a17" correct="true"/>
      <answer source="a18" correct="false"/>
    </MultipleChoiceQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
<div id="instruction">
	Questions 7-12. Read the passage and look at the statements below. Choose TRUE - if the statement is true; FALSE - if the statement is false; NOT GIVEN - if the information is not given in the passage.
	</div>
</header>
	


<section id="readingText">
<img class="photo2" src="../media/RD_TFN_002.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>
<h1><p>BBC Experience</p></h1>
<div id="reading">
<p class="hangingIndent"><b>A</b>&#xA0;Situated beneath Broadcasting House in London, the BBC Experience is one long advertisement for the Beeb or a new interactive exhibition celebrating 75 years of broadcasting, depending on your frame of mind.</p>
<p class="hangingIndent"><b>B</b>&#xA0;Groups of up to 30 people are guided through a series of rooms, each one offering a different experience. First come a few static exhibits describing the early years of radio, followed by a multiscreen video diary of a typical day at Broadcasting House. Then the group gets the chance to record a short radio play, before moving into two rooms to watch a slide show relating the key events of the 20th century and the role of the BBC in reporting them. Finally, visitors are let loose in the interactive room where they can play with various gadgets and video games.</p>
<p class="hangingIndent"><b>C</b>&#xA0;The first two rooms are as exciting as watching a test-card transmission. To make things worse, visitors must spend 15 minutes in each room as all the dividing doors are operated by timers. However, the radio play can be great fun, particularly if you abandon your inhibitions. The slide show is artfully executed but hardly the cutting edge of technology.</p>
<p class="hangingIndent"><b>D</b>&#xA0;You can stay as long as you like in the interactive room. Some of the gadgets are enjoyable &#x2013; you can direct a scene from a soap opera, remix a music track, present the weather forecast, appear on a radio programme, commentate on a variety of sports events and operate the puppets on children's television.</p>
<p class="hangingIndent"><b>E</b>&#xA0;Groups leave every 15 minutes and you can buy tickets on the door or pre-book by phone. If you turn up at the busiest times (between 11am and 2pm), you may not get on the next tour.</p>
<p class="hangingIndent"><b>F</b>&#xA0;The exhibition is open 9.30am-5.30pm daily. The last group leaves at 5.30pm. Snacks and meals are available in the ground-floor cafe. Take the tube to Oxford Circus or Great Portland Street.</p>
</div>
<h7>Glossary</h7>
<ol id="splitreadingList">
<li>BBC: British Broadcasting Corporation. A publicly financed broadcasting organisation &#x2013; the first and biggest in Britain.</li>
<li>Broadcasting House: the headquarters of the BBC in London.</li>
<li>the Beeb: the informal name for the BBC.</li>
<li>test-card transmission: a still television picture broadcast outside normal programming hours and used to judge the quality of the image.</li>
<li>the tube: the underground train in London.</li>
</ol>
<p>Mark Hodson, The Sunday Times.</p>
</section>

<section id="body">
   
  <ol id="splitquestionList">
     
    <li id="q1">You have to join a group to see the exhibition.<list class="answerList"><li><a id="a1">True</a></li><li><a id="a2">False</a></li><li><a id="a3">Not given</a></li></list> </li>
     <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="q2">You can visit the rooms of the exhibition in any order.<list class="answerList"><li><a id="a4">True</a></li><li><a id="a5">False</a></li><li><a id="a6">Not given</a></li></list> </li>
     <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="q3">You can direct different types of television programme at the exhibition.<list class="answerList"><li><a id="a7">True</a></li><li><a id="a8">False</a></li><li><a id="a9">Not given</a></li></list> </li>
     <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="q4">You can meet radio and television personalities at the exhibition.<list class="answerList"><li><a id="a10">True</a></li><li><a id="a11">False</a></li><li><a id="a12">Not given</a></li></list> </li>
     <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="q5">There are four tours of the exhibition every hour.<list class="answerList"><li><a id="a13">True</a></li><li><a id="a14">False</a></li><li><a id="a15">Not given</a></li></list> </li>
     <p class="linespace"></p>
    <li id="q6">You have to book in advance to go on a tour of the exhibition.<list class="answerList"><li><a id="a16">True</a></li><li><a id="a17">False</a></li><li><a id="a18">Not given</a></li></list> </li>
	<p class="linespace"></p>
  </ol>
</section>

</body>
</bento>