<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="gapfill" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2012-01-16" />
	<meta name="customised" content="false" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen.css" type="text/css" media="screen" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/splitscreen-print.css" type="text/css" media="print" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
  <settings>
    <param name="delayedMarking" value="true"/>
  </settings>
  <questions>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q1" block="b1">
      <answer value="tungsten carbide" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q2" block="b2">
      <answer value="90 hours" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q3" block="b3">
      <answer value="ultrasonically cleaned" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q4" block="b4">
      <answer value="tiny grooves machined" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="grooves" correct="true"/>
      <answer value="tiny grooves" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
<div id="instruction">		
		Questions 11-14. Complete the labels on the diagram on the right, using NO MORE THAN THREE WORDS OR A NUMBER from the passage for each answer. Write your answers in gaps 11-14.
</div>
</header>

<section id="readingText">

  <h1><p>Fine line between Biro and fame</p></h1>
  
  <p>The ballpoint has a history of false starts and missed opportunities for its inventor.</p>
  <p>Second World War pilots found that fountain pens leaked at high altitude. The problem was solved in 1944 when an English accountant offered the Royal Air Force a new invention, the Biro.</p>
  <p>Henry George Martin had acquired the rights to the ballpoint from its inventor, Hungarian journalist Ladislo Biro, then living in Argentina. Biro had seen the quick drying ink used by printers, patenting his idea in 1938.</p>
  <p>Unknown to Biro and those who copied him, a similar device had been patented by John Loud in 1888. Loud's pen was intended to mark leather, but it was never commercially exploited, leaving Biro to make his mark on the world.</p>
  <p>Biro made two big mistakes &#x2013; he failed to get a US patent for the ballpoint, and he distributed samples months ahead of launch.</p>
  <p>This gave Chicago businessman Milton Reynolds, who had seen a sample, time to market his own version in the US ahead of Biro.</p>
  <p>The battle between Biro and Reynolds was fierce and costly, not helped by the fact that neither was able to make ballpoints which were reliable. The public soon returned to the fountain pen and Biro concentrated on surrealist painting.</p>
  <p>Enter Marcel Bich, the former production manager of a French ink company, who had set up his own business in Paris making fountain pens and propelling pencils. Italian-born Baron Bich launched his own improved Biro in Europe in 1949. He called it after himself, but shortened the name to Bic and was hugely successful.</p>
  <p>In 1957 Bich acquired the rights to the original Biro when this company, Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; Bic, took over the Biro Swan Company, the result of a merger between the Miles Martin Aircraft Company, which had made the Biros for the RAF, and the Swan Pen Company. Miles Martin had made the RAF ballpoints in a hangar at Woodley, near Reading, using staff from the Lunn travel agency, which was owned by a friend of Martin.</p>
  <p>In 1960 Bich started selling his ballpoint pens in the US. Customers were reluctant to buy until he launched a TV advertising campaign with the slogan: 'Writes first time, every time and for only 29 cents.'</p>
  <p>Bich bought the Waterman Pen Company in the US. He encountered very little competition except from companies such as Parker Pens which were selling luxury ballpoints for several dollars apiece.</p>
  <p>The Bic Biro looks simple, but batches of the tungsten carbide balls can take up to 90 hours to make. They are fitted in brass housings, which are ultrasonically cleaned and then shaped to prevent the ball from slipping out. Tiny grooves machined in the housing let the ink flow.  On top of that there is the plastic casing, the tubes of ink, the stopper and the air hole.</p>
  <p>Bic went on to make its first disposable cigarette lighters in 1973, sold initially under the slogan 'Flick your Bic'. In 1975 it started to make one-piece disposable razors. Today it makes 8m razors and 4m lighters a day.</p>
  <p>It promotes the Bic name in the leisure industry, sponsoring American football and the Prost-Peugeot Formula 1 motor racing team. It also makes windsurfing boards, reflecting Bich's own interest in sailing.</p>
  <p>Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; Bic is now one of France's leading quoted companies, and Bic itself is the third best known French trademark. The company has added names such as Shaeffer, the US pen maker, and Tipp-Ex, the German correcting fluid company, to its stable.</p>
  <p>The keys to Bich's success were his knowledge of inks, his production expertise and his early use of plastics, enabling him to produce reliable products in vast numbers at low cost. It is ironic that the product he made world famous is still known by the name of the man who was unable to make it work properly &#x2013; Biro.</p>
  <p>Nicholas Bannister, The Guardian</p>

</section>
	
<section id="body">
  <img class="leftFloat" src="../media/WB_GR_005.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>
  <p class="linespace"></p>
    <ol id="splitquestionList">
  <p>11.<tab/><input id="q1"/></p>
  <p class="linespace"></p>
  <p>12.<tab/><input id="q2"/></p>
  <p class="linespace"></p>
  <p>13.<tab/><input id="q3"/></p>
  <p class="linespace"></p>
  <p>14.<tab/><input id="q4"/></p>
  <p class="linespace"></p>
	</ol>
</section>

</body>
</bento>