<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="gapfill" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-11-14" />
	<meta name="customised" content="false" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking/>
		<feedback groupbased="true" wrongonly="false"/>
		<buttons/>
		<exercise samelengthgaps="true"/>
		<misc splitscreen="true"/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
  <questions>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q1" block="b1">
      <answer value="ix" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q2" block="b2">
      <answer value="i" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q3" block="b3">
      <answer value="xi" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q4" block="b4">
      <answer value="v" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q5" block="b5">
      <answer value="viii" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q6" block="b6">
      <answer value="ii" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q7" block="b7">
      <answer value="vii" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
    <GapFillQuestion source="q8" block="b8">
      <answer value="iv" correct="true"/>
    </GapFillQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	
		
		Questions 1-8. The reading passage has eight paragraphs A-H. Choose the most suitable headings for paragraphs A-H from the list of headings on the right. Write the appropriate numbers (i-xi). There are more headings than paragraphs, so you will not use them all.
		
</header>
	
<section id="body">
  <br/>
  <ol id="questionList">
    <li id="1">Paragraph A <input id="q1"/></li>
    <li id="2">Paragraph B <input id="q2"/></li>
    <li id="3">Paragraph C <input id="q3"/></li>
    <li id="4">Paragraph D <input id="q4"/></li>
    <li id="5">Paragraph E <input id="q5"/></li>
    <li id="6">Paragraph F <input id="q6"/></li>
    <li id="7">Paragraph G <input id="q7"/></li>
    <li id="8">Paragraph H <input id="q8"/></li>
  </ol>
</section>

<section id="readingText"><p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>Robomoths</b></font></p><p align="left"><font color="#000000"><b>A</b> With rare exceptions, such as bees and silkworms, the insect world is a source of pests rather than of pets or pack animals. In an age of miniaturisation, however, a few researchers are wondering if more insects might be harnessed to the service of man. One is John Hildebrand, a neurobiologist at the University of Arizona. As part of a project run by America's Defence Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA), he and his colleagues have been working with the giant sphinx moth to create a "biobot" &#x2013; an animal that can be controlled electronically by a human. They have designed a radio transmitter small enough to attach to a sphinx moth without impairing its ability to fly. The next stage is to add a receiver to tell the moth where to go.</font></p><p align="left"><font color="#000000"><b>B</b> Moths may not be that bright, but Dr Hildebrand believes they can be manipulated in rather the same way as a donkey is by dangling a carrot in front of its head. The "carrot" he proposes is a sex pheromone &#x2013; a mixture of chemicals that female sphinx moths give off to attract males. It is potent stuff. Previous research has shown that a few molecules are enough to attract a male's attention, and that, given a favourable wind, an amorous male can find a mate who is several kilometres away.</font></p><p align="left"><b>C</b> One of the team's ideas is to fit male sphinx moths with small, radio-controlled pheromone dispensers. A moth's pheromone-detectors are its antennae. It can work out where pheromone molecules are coming from by comparing the signals from each antenna, in the same way that a person works out the direction of a sound by comparing signals from each ear. A moth's senses could be subverted by puffing suitable molecules from a dispenser to steer it towards a chosen target.</p><p align="left"><font color="#000000"><b>D </b> That is a rather crude approach. Dr Hildebrand hopes to be more subtle. He has spent much of his career examining how a moth's nervous system responds to the pheromone, and he thinks he knows enough to steer a moth directly, without the need for the chemicals themselves. He plans to do it by attaching electrodes to the nerves involved and stimulating them appropriately &#x2013; turning the moth into a genuine, radio-controlled biobot.</font></p><p align="left"><b>E</b> That would be an interesting demonstration of mankind's powers over nature. Could it also be useful? Brian Smith and his colleagues at Ohio State University have recently shown that sphinx moths can be manipulated like dogs as well as donkeys. Pavlov's early experiments on reflexes trained dogs to salivate at the sound of a bell, by ringing one every time they were fed with meat. Dr Smith's team has mimicked Pavlov by training moths to stick their tongues out in response to a chemical called cyclohexanone, which was puffed at them while they were fed sugared water.</p><p align="left"><font color="#000000"><b>F</b> The reason that this trick might be useful &#x2013; and the reason for DARPA's interest &#x2013; is that cyclohexanone is a volatile component of TNT, an explosive often used in landmines. By releasing a swarm of trained moths over a minefield, and observing where they stuck their tongues out, it should be possible to locate mines without risk either to people or to expensive mine-detecting machinery.</font></p><p align="left"><b>G</b> It is hard to see if a moth is sticking its tongue out at a range of several hundred metres. But Dr Smith has thought of a way round that. He can sense when a moth is blowing a raspberry by attaching a wire to the muscle that controls the insect's tongue, and using it to transmit a signal via one of Dr Hildebrand's tiny electronic backpacks.</p><p align="left"><font color="#000000"><b>H</b> If lepidopteran mine detectors work, they could be the start of a new industry. The rate at which video cameras are being miniaturised means that they, too, may soon be light enough for insects to carry. That would have obvious military applications, even if one countermeasure is obvious, too: surrounding sensitive installations with giant candles.</font></p><p align="left"> landmine: a bomb which is hidden in the ground and explodes when a person or vehicle passes over it.</p>2 lepidopteran: of the insect order Lepidoptera, which includes butterflies and moths, that as adults have four wings usually covered with tiny scales.<p align="left">The Economist, 4th March 2000.</p></section>

<section id="rt2001"><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">By doing this exercise first you will have a good idea about the general content and organisation of the text. This is important because, with eight paragraphs, this is a fairly long passage. The list of headings probably seems quite long at first sight, but don't panic. If you do the task in an organised way, it's not so difficult.</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Reading through the list, you should begin to notice that there are pairs of headings that share a theme:</font></p><p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Facts about moths:</font></p>i. What attracts a moth?vi. Lepidopteran mating rituals<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Scientists and their work:</font></p>x. Smith's work with dogs and donkeysiii. Pavlov's work with mothsix. Hildebrand's achievements so far<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Steering:</font></p>v. More sophisticated steeringxi. A crude approach to steering<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Using insects:</font></p>iv. Future work for insectsii. Moths could save lives<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Other:</font></p>vii. A solution to a problemviii. Stimulus and response<p align="left"><font face="verdana" size="13" color="#000000">Organised like this, the list doesn't seem so long or difficult to deal with. Now you can search the text for paragraphs that match a theme, for example 'steering', by scanning for key words. When you have found the word 'steering', read carefully to find out which of the two 'steering' headings match. Do the same for each theme.</font></p></section>

</body>
</bento>