<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion-from" content="targetspotting" />
	<meta name="conversion-date" content="2011-11-10" />
	<meta name="customised" content="true" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/targetspotting.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking/>
		<feedback wrongonly="false"/>
		<buttons feedback="true" marking="true"/>
		<exercise/>
		<misc timed="150"/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
  <questions>
    <TargetSpottingQuestion block="b1">
      <answer source="t1" correct="false">
        <feedback source="fb1"/>
      </answer>
    </TargetSpottingQuestion>
    <TargetSpottingQuestion block="b2">
      <answer source="t2" correct="true">
        <feedback source="fb2"/>
      </answer>
    </TargetSpottingQuestion>
    <TargetSpottingQuestion block="b3">
      <answer source="t3" correct="true">
        <feedback source="fb3"/>
      </answer>
    </TargetSpottingQuestion>
    <TargetSpottingQuestion block="b4">
      <answer source="t4" correct="false">
        <feedback source="fb4"/>
      </answer>
    </TargetSpottingQuestion>
    <TargetSpottingQuestion block="b5">
      <answer source="t5" correct="true">
        <feedback source="fb5"/>
      </answer>
    </TargetSpottingQuestion>
    <TargetSpottingQuestion block="b6">
      <answer source="t6" correct="false">
        <feedback source="fb6"/>
      </answer>
    </TargetSpottingQuestion>
    <TargetSpottingQuestion block="b7">
      <answer source="t7" correct="true">
        <feedback source="fb7"/>
      </answer>
    </TargetSpottingQuestion>
  </questions>
</script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	
		
		Questions 1-4. Listen to the recording, which will play automatically, and follow the instructions. Click FOUR letters A-G.
		
</header>
	
<section id="body">
  <audio controls="compact" src="../media/ST_LN2a.mp3" mode="4" id="1002"/>
  <img class="rightFloat" src="../media/ST_LN_005.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"/>
  
  
  
    <h7><p>1 - 4 Which FOUR advantages of having a web site are mentioned by the speaker?</p></h7>
	
	<ol id="targetspotting">
		<list class="answerList"><li><g id="t1">Fewer employees are needed.</g></li>
    <li><g id="t2">It is an inexpensive form of publicity.</g></li>
    <li><g id="t3">Small companies can compete with large international ones.</g></li>
    <li><g id="t4">Companies can do business 24 hours a day, 365 days a year.</g></li>
    <li><g id="t5">Far more potential customers have access to your products.</g></li>
    <li><g id="t6">It is easier to adapt products and services to the market.</g></li>
    <li><g id="t7">Information needed by customers can be kept up-to-date.</g></li></list>
	</ol>
  
  
</section>

<section id="fb1">
  <p align="left">A. The speaker says that you don't have to employ a professional programmer. In other words, you don't need to employ additional staff. She does not say anything about being able to reduce staff.</p>
</section>

<section id="fb2">
  <p align="left">B. The speaker says that it's a 'comparatively low-cost way to advertise' and 'low-cost' has a similar meaning to 'inexpensive'.</p>
</section>

<section id="fb3">
  <p align="left">C. The speaker says that the web sites of small companies need not be any different to those of larger companies and so they can be just as impressive. In other words, just as competitive.</p>
</section>

<section id="fb4">
  <p align="left">D. The speaker does not mention this.</p>
</section>

<section id="fb5">
  <p align="left">E. The speaker says that a web site gives a much greater number of customers the possibility of buying the products and that people anywhere in the world can find out about these products.</p>
</section>

<section id="fb6">
  <p align="left">F. The speaker says its easier to revise and update the web pages not the products and services.</p>
</section>

<section id="fb7">
  <p align="left">G. The speaker says that you can quickly and easily change the information on your web site and keep customers informed. In other words keep them up-to-date.</p>
</section>

<section id="rt2001">
  <p align="left">You should be able to see from the question and the possible answers that you will hear someone talking about the advantages of a web site on the World Wide Web.</p>
  <p align="left">Questions 1 - 4The statements here from A to G might all seem to be advantages so you need to be familiar with them so you can recognise the ones that are mentioned. Are there any that you could eliminate? What about 'F'? Why would having a web site make it easier to adapt products? Which do you think are the greatest advantages out of this list?</p>
</section>

</body>
</bento>