<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bento xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
	<meta name="conversion" type="gapfill" date="2011-10-27" />
	<link rel="stylesheet" href="../../css/exercises.css" type="text/css" />
	<style type="text/css">
	<![CDATA[
		/*
		 * List any exercise specific css here
		 */			
	]]>
	</style>
	<script id="settings" type="application/xml">
		<settings>
		<marking/>
		<feedback wrongonly="false"/>
		<buttons/>
		<exercise/>
		<misc/>
	</settings>
	</script>
	<br/>
<script id="model" type="application/xml">
<questions><GapFillQuestion source="q1"><answer value="strike " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q2"><answer value="overbooked " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q3"><answer value="bomb threat " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q4"><answer value="technical problem " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q5"><answer value="air rage " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q6"><answer value="turbulence " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q7"><answer value="air sickness " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q8"><answer value="recycled air " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q9"><answer value="near misses " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q10"><answer value="thrombosis " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion><GapFillQuestion source="q11"><answer value="jet lag " correct="true"/></GapFillQuestion></questions></script>

</head>
<body>
	
<header>
	Complete the magazine article by filling each gap with the correct word or phrase.
</header>
	
<section id="body">
	<img class="rightFloat" src="../media/TT_TV_006.jpg" mode="1" id="1001"  /><p align="left"><font color="#0000ff"><b>The Perils of Flying</b></font></p><p align="left">On a particularly eventful trip recently I began to wonder if air travel really is as convenient as they say. Before you even get to the airport your plane can be delayed or even cancelled because the crew are on <input id="q1" /> over pay. </p><p align="left">Or, having booked your tickets months in advance, you arrive at the airport only to be informed that there are no seats left - the flight is <input id="q2" /> and you'll just have to wait for the next one. Or you may get to the front of the queue at the check-in desk, as I did, to be told that the building has to be evacuated as they've just received a <input id="q3" />.</p><p align="left">When you eventually make it to the departure lounge, your troubles may still not be over. Once there, you learn that your aircraft has a <input id="q4" /> and that it'll be fixed in twenty minutes, then another twenty minutes, and then another, and so on. Even if you're lucky enough to be sitting on the plane at this stage, you could now be subject to a display of <input id="q5" /> as passengers run out of patience and start shouting at the cabin crew.</p><p align="left">And this is all before you've even taken off. What about once you're airborne? There's an endless list of things that can go wrong. Your fellow passengers may not be the most considerate, for one. Your plane doesn't have to hit a pocket of air <input id="q6" /> for your cocktail or coffee to land in your lap. You could have this experience courtesy of the passenger in front who shoots their seat back without warning. </p><p align="left">You might also be unlucky enough to find yourself sitting next to someone who suffers from <input id="q7" />. And you don't have to be in a seat near someone with an infectious illness to catch it - you can do that just by breathing in the <input id="q8" /> in the cabin.</p><p align="left"><font color="#000000">Presuming you land without incident (although with so many flights taking off and landing at some airports, you'll wonder why far more <input id="q9" /> aren't reported) you could now, due to the late arrival of your plane, have missed your connection and end up spending the night at the airport waiting for the next available flight. </font></p><p align="left">You might also be one of those unlucky passengers who, after sitting in a cramped seat for hours on a long-haul flight, develop <input id="q10" /> which can be fatal. And then, of course, there's the inevitable <input id="q11" /> that most of us will suffer from for days afterwards.</p><p align="left"><font size="2"></font></p>
</section>
</body>
</bento>